一如既往的错误
Wrong, as usual.
美国在东欧问题上的不作为
The United States' lack of action in Eastern Europe...
证明了苏联在阿富汗边界的侵略
...proves that the Soviet Union's aggression at the Afghan border...
不会被美国公开反对
...will not be opposed publicly by the United States.
下一条消息
Issue:
苏联继续进行其最近的一系列军事演习
The Soviet Union continued its recent series of military exercises...
今天在白令海进行了一次爆炸试验
... conducting a bomb test today in the Bering Sea...
离阿拉斯加南海岸仅1500英里
... just 1500 miles off the southern coast of Alaska.
总统理查德·尼克松对苏联发布如下警告
President Richard Nixon issued this warning to the Soviets:
美国不主动挑起斗争
The United States does not start fights.
我必须强调
Let it be clear
我们保存自己的实力
Let it be clear we maintain our strength...
是为了维护和平
...in order to maintain peace...
所以任何对手 都应该问问自己
...so any adversary should ask themselves:
攻击美国带来的后果
"Do the consequences of attacking America...
是否高于可能带来的好处
...outweigh the potential benefits?"
苏联的行动导致了一个结果
As a result of the Soviet activity...
核能科学家监察小组
...the watchdog group of nuclear scientists...
将"末日时钟"的指针拨到了午夜前5分钟
... moved the Doomsday Clock up to five minutes until midnight:
午夜代表核战带来的毁灭
Destruction by nuclear war.
问题
Question:
用0到10来衡量
On a scale of zero to 10
0表示不可能…
zero meaning impossibility...
10代表完全的确信
...10 meaning complete metaphysical certitude...
苏联向美国发起攻击
...what are the chances the Russians
的几率到底有多大?
will actually attack the United States?
帕特·布坎南
Pat Buchanan.
零
Zero.
苏联绝不会冒险发起战争
The Soviets would never risk going to war...
因为有一件行走的核威慑
...when we have a walking nuclear deterrent
站在我们这边
on our side.
你说的当然是曼哈顿博士
You're referring, of course, to Dr. Manhattan...
但是曼哈顿博士的存在
... but does Dr. Manhattan's existence
一定能保证世界和平吗
guarantee world peace?
艾琳娜·克里夫特
Eleanor Clift.
然而这并没有阻止苏联继续
Well, it hasn't stopped the Soviet Union...
囤积破纪录数量的核武器
... from stockpiling record amounts of nuclear weapons.
你不觉得那只是摆摆样子吗
You don't think it's just posturing?
也许苏联之所以…
Maybe the reason why the Soviets...
搞这些炸弹试验…
...are doing these bomb tests...
就是因为害怕曼哈顿博士
...is because they feel threatened by Dr. Manhattan.
或许全世界都有这样的感觉
Maybe the whole world feels like that.
苏联的船只已经侵犯了领海
Soviet ships have violated the territorial waters...
看来该来的早晚都会来
Just a matter of time, I suppose.
这就是个笑话
It's a joke.
全都是笑话
It's all a joke.
母亲 原谅我
Mother, forgive me.
(罪犯们拜倒在丝灵脚下)
民兵联盟
守望者
(日本投降)
(侧影女侠)
(美钞队长)
退休愉快 莎莉
(飞蛾侠)
(侧影被杀)
(墙上血字：同性恋 婊子)
(纽约公报：苏联有原子弹了)
(幼年罗夏)
(肯尼迪和曼哈顿博士)
(笑匠)
我曾经也是个英雄 该死的
SALLY: I was a hero, goddamn it!
此举明显是向西贡政府发出信号…
MAN [ON TV]:an act clearly meant to send a signal to the government in Saigon...
(越战升级)
暴力和镇压不是和平之道
... that violence and oppression is not the way to peace.
(古巴首领卡斯特罗访苏)
(尼克松需要修理)
(安迪·沃霍尔)
祝你好运 戈斯基先生
Good luck, Mr. Gorsky.
(法老王)
(新一代守望者)
(尼克松第三次当选总统)
从这里滚出去 义警们
MAN: Get out of here, vigilantes!
(谁来看守"守望者")
导演: 扎克·施耐德
不
No!
爱德华·布雷克 67岁 6尺2寸 重225磅
GALLAGHER: Edward Blake. Sixty-seven years old. Six-two, a solid 225.
这家伙结实得像个橄榄球后卫
Guy was built like a linebacker.
对 我看过尸体了
FINE: Yeah, I saw the body.
按他这年纪的人来说 身材保持得很好
For a guy his age, he was in terrific shape.
你是说 除了他死了这一点?
GALLAGHER: You mean apart from being dead?
那是厚玻璃板
That's plate glass.
你得踩油门才能撞出条缝来
You'd have to step on the gas just to put a crack in it.
一定是被扔出去的
Had to have been thrown.
检查过卧室了吗?
Check the bedroom?
是的 抽屉都被打开了 翻了个底朝天
Yeah. Drawers opened, tossed through.
床垫被翻过 大概是入室抢劫
Mattress flipped. Probably robbery.
或者做成入室抢劫一样
Or made to look like one.
看看这个
See this?
- 和总统握手 - 哇
- Shaking hands with the president. FINE: Whoa.
觉得布雷克是密探?
Think Blake was a spook?
政府的还是地下组织的?
Government or black ops?
我觉得…
GALLAGHER: I think...
这件事远远大过你我
...this is way bigger than both of us.
罗夏日记 10月12日 1985年
RORSCHACH: Rorschach's journal, October 12th, 1985.
今早巷子里有狗尸 被车轮碾爆肚皮
Dog carcass in alley this morning. Tire tread on burst stomach.
这座城市害怕我
This city's afraid of me.
我见过它的真面目 这些街道就是无尽的臭水沟…
I've seen its true face. The streets are extended gutters...
充满鲜血的臭水沟
... and the gutters are full of blood.
当这些污垢终于结痂时…
And when the drains finally scab over...
所有的害虫都会淹溺
... all the vermin will drown.
他们的色情和谋杀所沉积的污秽…
The accumulated filth of all their sex and murder...
会在他们的腰部泛起泡沫…
... will foam up around their waists...
这时所有的婊子和政客们就会抬头哭喊： "救救我们！"
... and all the whores and politicians will look up and shout, "Save us."
而我只会轻声回应："不"
And I'll whisper, "No."
现在整个世界处于深渊边缘…
Now the whole world stands on the brink...
向下盯着血腥的地狱
... staring down into bloody hell.
那些自由主义者、知识分子…
All those liberals and intellectuals...
那些能说会道的人…
... and smooth talkers...
突然之间哑口无言了
... and all of a sudden, nobody can think of anything to say.
在我脚下 这座可怕的城市…
Beneath me, this awful city.
它惨叫连连 如同满是弱智儿童的屠宰场
It screams like an abattoir full of retarded children...
夜晚散发出通奸和丧良心的臭气
... and the night reeks of fornication and bad consciences.
(笑匠笑到了最后：罪犯头目摩罗神受到了正义的制裁)
(民兵联盟)
今晚 笑匠死在了纽约
Tonight, a comedian died in New York.
某人知道原因
Somebody knows why.
某人知道
Somebody knows.
不 我肯定听到了些动静
No, I definitely heard something.
看住门
Watch the door.
嘘
Shh.
一定是风吹的 下次你…
Must've been the wind. Next time you...
一切起源于那些帮派团伙
MAN: It all started with the gangs.
你知道 大家往往忘记这点
You know, people tend to forget that.
海盗装扮、鬼魂
Pirate outfits, ghosts.
他们以为那样好玩 装扮起来去打劫
They thought it was funny: Dress up and pull heists.
就算我们抓了他们 也很快又回到街头
As soon as we'd arrest them, they'd be back on the street.
没人能指认出他们 因为戴着该死的面具
Nobody could pick them out of a lineup because of the damn masks.
所以我们几个警察 聚在一起…
So a few of us cops, we get together...
我们合计 去他妈的 我们也蒙面
...and we figure, what the heck, we'll mask up, too.
我们去完成法律做不到的事情
We'll finish what the law couldn't.
很快 报纸也收到风声 他们大肆报道…
Pretty soon, the papers get wind of it. They ran with it...
噢 老天 我们变得全国出名了
...and oh, boy, we're a national pastime.
那时有我、美钞、飞蛾侠…
It was me, Dollar Bill, Mothman...
都会队长、兜帽判官…
...Captain Metropolis, Hooded Justice...
丝灵
...Silk Spectre
还有笑匠
and the Comedian.
噢 别让我提到他
Oh, don't get me started on him.
我一定喝醉了 又向你说起这些伤心事
I must be drunk already, telling you this sob story again.
我觉得你是想表达一个观点
I think you were trying to make a point.
好吧 我的观点是 我们起头太容易了
Well, my point is that we had it too easy.
发生在你们身上的事情不公平
It wasn't fair what happened to you guys...
你们接手的是我们留下的烂摊子
You guys who picked up where we left off.
还有尼克松强迫你们引退
With Nixon forcing you out.
尼克松 噢 那个烂人
Nixon, oh, that prick.
想想我五次投票给这烂人
To think I voted for that prick five times.
嘿 不选他就只有共产党了 对吧?
Hey, it was him or the commies, right?
噢 差不多到午夜了 该走了
Oh, wow, it's almost midnight. Gotta go.
要真话吗?
Truth?
你当夜枭比我当得更好 丹尼小子
You were a better Nite Owl than I ever was, Danny boy.
霍利斯 我们都知道这是屁话
Hollis, we both know that's bullshit.
嘿 少说脏话
Hey. Watch it with the language.
这可是打趴过轴心队长的左勾拳 记得吗?
This is the left hook that floored Captain Axis, remember?
最新报道
WOMAN ON TV: This just in:
那位被称作"罗夏"的蒙面义警…
The masked vigilante known as Rorschach...
在凌晨时分袭击了一位警官
... has assaulted a police officer in the early-morning hours.
罗夏在FBI通缉名单的前十名…
Rorschach is on the FBI's Ten Most Wanted list...
因他违反六年前发布的取缔蒙面英雄的"基恩法案"
... for violation of the Keene Act, which banned masked heroes six years ago.
据报道罗夏打残了一位警官
Rorschach reportedly incapacitated...
法案迫使大家都退出了 除了他
Forced everyone out except him.
噢 他会退出的
Oh, he'll quit.
在他死的时候
When he's dead.
- 下周见?  - 其实…
DAN: Next week? HOLLIS: Well...
你看 你没必要一直这样陪我
...you know, you don't have to keep humoring me like this.
如果你有个热辣的约会对象之类的…
If you got a hot date or something...
嘿 我们退休人员应该团结一点 不是吗?
Hey, us retired guys have to stick together, right?
你想念那些日子吗?
You ever miss it?
没 你呢?
No. You?
噢 去它的 没
Oh, heck, no.
回见了
Be seeing you.
(梅森汽修)
(专修老车)
(乡愁：维特公司出品)
你好 丹尼尔
Hello, Daniel.
罗夏
Rorschach.
给自己弄了些豆子 希望你别介意
Helped myself to some beans. Hope you don't mind.
不 不 当然不介意
No, no. Course not.
你要我给你热热吗?
You want me to heat those up for you?
这样就好
Fine like this.
最近在忙些什么?
How have you been keeping?
忙着远离牢房
RORSCHACH: Out of prison.
在新闻里听到你了
Heard about you on the news.
说你袭击了一个警察
Say you attacked a cop.
轻伤 都不用住院治疗
RORSCHACH: Minor wound. Won't need hospitalization.
丹尼尔…
Daniel...
看看这个
...Iook at this.
- 这是豆汁吗?  - 这是"人汁"
DAN: Is this bean juice? RORSCHACH: Human bean juice.
徽章是笑匠的 血也是 他死了
Badge belonged to the Comedian. Blood too. He's dead.
我们到下面谈吧
Let's talk downstairs.
可能是入室行窃
DAN: It could have been a burglary.
或许凶手不知道笑匠是谁
Maybe the killer didn't know who the Comedian was.
一个普通入室窃贼? 杀了笑匠? 荒谬
RORSCHACH: An ordinary burglar? Kill the Comedian? Ridiculous.
我听说他从1977年一直为政府做事…
I heard he'd been working for the government since '77...
推翻南美洲的马克思主义共和国
...knocking over Marxist republics in South America.
或许这是一起政治谋杀什么的
Maybe it was a political killing or something.
或许
Maybe.
或许有人正在除掉变装英雄
Maybe someone's picking off costumed heroes.
你不觉得有点被害妄想吗
DAN: You don't think that's a little paranoid?
他们是这样说我的吗
That what they say about me now?
被害妄想症
Paranoid?
听着 笑匠在那些日子里树敌很多…
DAN: Look, Comedian made a lot of enemies over the years...
甚至得罪了些朋友
...even among his friends.
说起朋友 霍利斯·梅森还好吗?
RORSCHACH: Speaking of friends, how's Hollis Mason?
他写了那本书 里面说了些笑匠的坏话
He wrote that book. Said some bad things about the Comedian in it.
我不喜欢你暗示的东西
I don't like what you're implying,
另外我喜欢少被人跟踪
and I like being followed even less.
也许我是在照看着你
Maybe I was keeping an eye on you
以防万一有人在捕杀面具英雄
in case someone's gunning for masks.
你以前没这么感情用事
You were never that sentimental.
袭击一个 就是袭击我们全部
Attack on one is attack on all of us.
那你建议我们该干些什么?
What do you suggest we do about it?
报复
Retribution.
守望者已经完了
Watchmen are over.
狡猾的尼克松说的
Says Tricky Dick.
我说的
Says me.
没人知道你是谁
Nobody knows who you are.
你可以放弃 试试过正常生活
You can give it up, try and have a normal life.
就像你过的生活? 正常生活?
That what you have now? A normal life?
当你走在狂犬病肆虐的城市街道上…
When you walk down the street in a city dying of rabies...
路过那些人渣败类…
...past the human cockroaches...
听他们谈论着海洛因和儿童色情…
...talking about their heroin and child pornography...
你真觉得很正常吗?
...do you really feel normal?
至少我没有继续躲在面具后面
Least I'm not the one still hiding behind a mask.
不
No.
你躲在大众这副面具后面
You're hiding in plain sight.
回头见 丹
Be seeing you, Dan.
北边两个街区外 有个维修竖井能出去
A maintenance hatch will let you out two blocks north.
对 我还记得
Yeah, I remember.
以前常来这里
Came here often,
那时候我们还是搭档
Came here often, when we were partners.
那的确是段好时光 罗夏
Those were great times, huh, Rorschach?
后来怎么了
What happened?
你退出了
You quit.
罗夏日记
Rorschach's journal.
第一次访友无功而返
First visit of evening fruitless.
感觉有点低落
Feel slightly depressed.
很快就会有战争
Soon there will be war.
上百万的人会在疾病和痛苦中惨死
Millions will perish in sickness and misery.
为什么一个人的死还比这么多人重要?
Why does one death matter against so many?
因为有好人有坏人 而坏人必须受到惩罚
Because there is good and evil, and evil must be punished.
即使面对世界末日…
Even in the face of armageddon...
在这点上我也不会妥协
... I will not compromise in this.
[片段1开始][时长][0:03:04.56][目标][0:23:48.74]
[片段1结束][时长][0:03:04.56][目标][0:23:48.74]
维特先生
MAN: Mr. Veidt...
迄今为止 你是守望者当中唯二…
...to date, you're one of only two Watchmen...
向大众公开真实身份的成员之一
...ever to reveal their true identity to the world...
第一位是霍利斯·梅森
...the first being Hollis Mason.
将自己超级英雄"法老王"的一面…
And you've certainly profited greatly by it...
转变成亿万产业 你一定从中获益不少
...turning your superhero alter ego, Ozymandias, into a billion-dollar industry:
玩具、午餐盒、基因工程
Toys, lunchboxes, genetic engineering.
我听说甚至有一部电影正在制作中
I understand there's even a movie in the works.
我没听到问问题 罗斯先生
I'm not hearing a question, Mr. Roth.
抱歉 你是否想过…
ROTH: I'm sorry. Do you think...
守望者会因我贱卖他们的奋斗而憎恨我?
The Watchmen resent me for prostituting their struggle?
(时事杂志：超人们为和平而联手)
这是个合理的问题 是的 我曾这样想过
It's a fair question. Yes, it's crossed my mind...
某些过往的同事或许会这样看待我
...some of my old colleagues might see it that way...
正如你也很清楚 有偏向的新闻报道…
...just as you're clearly aware that biased journalism...
让杂志更好卖
...sells more magazines.
维特产业的销售部
The merchandising arm of Veidt Industries
正在资助一项与曼哈顿博士合作的研究
is funding our work with Dr. Manhattan.
最近我们扩大了在南极洲的研究设施
We recently expanded our research facility in Antarctica...
希望研发出便宜、可再生的能源
...in the hope of developing cheap, renewable sources of energy...
这样我们可能结束全球对于石化燃料的依赖
...that we might eliminate the world's reliance on fossil fuels.
你看 就算不是政治学专家也能看出来
Now, it doesn't take a political scientist to see that
我们与苏联的冷战并非意识形态上的
our Cold War with the Russians isn't ideological...
而是基于恐惧 恐惧自己拥有的不够多
...it's based upon fear. Fear of not having enough.
但如果我们让资源变得无限
But if we make resources infinite...
啊…
...ah...
战争就会成为过去式
...we make war obsolete.
我希望其他的守望者们能明白这点
I would hope the other Watchmen understand that...
不管他们现在身处何方
...wherever they may be.
感谢你们抽空到来
Thanks for your time.
- 你样子不错 阿德里安 - 丹
- You look good, Adrian. - Dan.
好久不见了
It's been too long.
(纽约公报："末日时钟" 指向午夜前5分钟)
所以 罗夏认为有人在捕杀守望者 是吧?
ADRIAN: So Rorschach thinks someone's hunting the Watchmen, huh?
你认为可能吗?
You think it's possible?
统计学来讲 一桩谋杀并不等于一个趋势
Statistically, one murder doesn't equal a trend.
罗夏是个反社会份子 丹
Rorschach's a sociopath, Dan.
笑匠也是 他简直就是个纳粹
And so was the Comedian. He was practically a Nazi.
你比任何人都清楚这点
You know that better than anyone.
我来这里并不是因为我怀念他
I'm not here because I miss him.
这件事让罗夏想到…
It's occurred to Rorschach...
只有我们几个人知道彼此的身份
...that we're the only ones who know each other's identities.
而实际上 全世界的人都知道你的
Actually, the whole world knows yours.
所以我第一个要提醒你
That's why I'm warning you first.
谢谢你 丹
Thank you, Dan...
但现在我有更现实的东西需要担心
...but I fear there's something much more real to worry about...
比罗夏的蒙面英雄杀手更可怕
...than Rorschach's mask killer.
如果苏联真的发射了核弹
If the Russians do launch their nukes,
乔恩可以阻止吗?
can Jon really stop them?
苏联有5万1千枚核弹头储备
The Soviets have 51,000 warheads stockpiled.
就算乔恩拦截了其中的99%…
Even if Jon stops 99 percent of them...
那漏网的1%还是能杀死地球上所有生命
...the 1 percent that get through could still kill every living thing on Earth.
就算是曼哈顿博士也不能同时身处各方
Even Dr. Manhattan can't be everywhere at once.
(美国陆军洛克菲勒军事研究中心)
罗夏日记 10月13日 1985年
Rorschach's journal, October 13th, 1985...
晚上8:30
... 8:30 p.m.
与德雷伯格(夜枭)会面之后 嘴里滋味不太好
Meeting with Dreiberg left bad taste in mouth.
一个在躲地下室里哭泣的软弱失败者
A flabby failure who sits whimpering in his basement.
为什么我们之中就没剩几个...
Why are so few of us left active...
能保持活跃 健康 没有人格缺陷?
... healthy and without personality disorders?
初代夜枭在经营一家汽修店
The first Night Owl runs an auto-repair shop.
丝灵一世则成了一个发福的老妓女
The first Silk Spectre is a bloated, aging whore...
在加州的一处疗养胜地等死
... dying in a California rest resort.
美钞被旋转门夹住了斗篷…
Dollar Bill got his cape stuck in a revolving door...
被当场枪杀
... where he got gunned down.
侧影 被谋杀…
Silhouette, murdered...
成了她不检点的生活方式的受害者
... a victim of her own indecent lifestyle.
飞蛾侠在缅因州的一所精神病院里
Mothman's in an asylum in Maine.
还有阿德里安·维特
Even Adrian Veidt,
可能是个同性恋
possible homosexual.
还需进一步调查
Must investigate further.
我的名单里就剩两个人了
Only two names remain on my list.
俩人合住在洛克菲勒
Both share private quarters
军事研究中心的私人宿舍里
at Rockefeller Military Research Center.
我要去找他们
I shall go to them.
我要去告诉那个坚不可摧的人
I shall go tell the indestructible man
有人要谋杀他
that someone plans to murder him.
晚上好 罗夏
JON: Good evening, Rorschach.
曼哈顿博士
Dr. Manhattan,
你知道我为什么来
you know why I'm here.
是的
JON: Yes...
但你会失望地离开
...but you're going to leave disappointed.
罗夏
Rorschach.
你不该来这里 你是个通缉犯
You shouldn't be here. You're a wanted man.
我也很高兴见到你 丝灵
Nice to see you too, Silk Spectre.
我有个一直在用的真名
I have a real name I've been using.
说说看
Try it.
你说了算 劳瑞
Whatever you say, Laurie.
你来这做什么?
What are you doing here?
笑匠死了
JON: The Comedian is dead.
罗夏希望我观察我的未来…
Rorschach wants me to look into my future...
看看那杀手会不会被公开指认
...see if the killer is ever publicly identified.
我已经警告过德雷伯格了 现在来警告你
Already warned Dreiberg. Came to warn you too.
就算我愿意帮忙…
Even if I wanted to help...
我的未来已经被某种时空干扰遮住了
...my future is blocked by some kind of temporal interference.
我无法看清
I cannot see it clearly.
干扰? 什么引起的?
Interference? Caused by what?
最有可能是因为核灾难
In all likelihood, nuclear holocaust.
如果美国和苏联全面开战…
If the United States and Soviet Union engage in all-out war...
引发的冲击波 会产生超光速粒子
...the resulting blast wave would produce a sudden burst of tachyons...
这些粒子能沿着你们眼中的时间逆向运动
...particles which travel backward through what you perceive as time...
从而模糊了我现在的视觉影像
...therefore obscuring my vision of the present.
我必须回去工作了
I must return to my work.
等一等
RORSCHACH: Wait a minute.
万一有人正是为了这个要清除我们呢
What if that's why someone wants us out of the way?
防止我们去阻止灾难
So we can't do anything to stop it?
再见 罗夏
Goodbye, Rorschach.
费了好大工夫进来见你们…
RORSCHACH: Took a lot of effort to get in here to see you.
我是不会走的…
I'm not leaving...
除非把话说完
- till I've had my say.
看来最近你有很多事情瞒着我
Seems like there's a lot of things you don't tell me these days.
我不想过早让你担心
I didn't wanna worry you prematurely.
如果阿德里安和我能解决能源危机
If Adrian and I can solve the energy crisis,
战争也许能避免
war may be averted.
但你总说所有时间是同时发生的
LAURIE: But you always say time is simultaneous.
如果真是这样 那你怎么能改变未来?
If that's true, then how can you change the future?
如果你能像我一样感知时间就好了
If only you could perceive time as I do.
请允许我向你展示
Please let me show you.
魔法 梦想 那就是我以前拥有的
Magic. Dreams. That is what I had before.
我曾经是个英雄 该死的
I was a hero, goddamn it!
你变老又不是我的错
It's not my fault you got old.
你有什么可抱怨的?
What do you have to complain about?
是我在供养你和你的小孩
I'm putting food on the table for you and your child.
你怎么不打电话给你的朋友艾迪
Why don't you call your friend Eddie.
也许他能给你更好的生活
Maybe he can give you a better life.
那是个错误 就那一次
It was a mistake. One time.
那个想要强奸你的男人…
Man tries to rape you...
停下
Stop!
你的思绪总是走向黑暗的地方…
Your mind goes to dark places...
而你还好奇我为什么把坏事瞒着你
...and you wonder why I keep the worst from you.
替我向丹问好
Say hello to Dan for me.
什么?
What?
你想邀请我和你去吃晚餐…
You wanna ask me to go to dinner with you...
就像我们以前一样…
...like we used to...
但你不会
...but you won't.
你知道我不能去的
You know I can't.
所以你会打电话给丹…
So you'll call Dan...
这是很自然的
...which is only natural.
你应该得到一位老朋友的慰籍
You deserve the comfort of an old friend.
丹·德雷伯格的桌位
LAURIE: Dan Dreiberg's table.
- 你知道他和H·J是… - 我完全不知道
DAN: Did you know that he and H.J. Were...? I had no idea.
你还记得那个疯子吗? 他怎么称呼自己来着?
You remember that crazy guy? What'd he call himself?
屠杀队长
Captain Carnage.
他总是假装是个超级恶棍 好让自己被暴打一顿
Used to pretend he was a supervillain just so he could get beat up?
是啊 他找过我一次 我没理他
Yeah, he tried that on me once. I just walked away.
于是他光天化日跟着我走了整条街…
He starts following me down the street in broad daylight...
喊着："惩罚我吧！惩罚我吧！"
...yelling, "Punish me! Punish me!"
我只说道："不 滚开。"
I'm just saying, "No, get lost."
天啊 后来他怎么了?
God, whatever happened to him?
噢 嗯 后来他去惹罗夏了…
Oh. Um... He pulled that on Rorschach...
罗夏就把他扔下了电梯井
...and Rorschach dropped him down an elevator shaft.
哦 天啊 这可就不好笑了
Oh, my God. That's not even funny.
- 还是有点好笑的 - 嗯
- It's a little funny. - Yep.
很庆幸我点了四腿鸡
WOMAN: I'm glad I ordered the four-legged chicken.
能再见到你真的很好
It's really good to see you again.
见到你也很高兴
It's great seeing you too.
我们为什么那样做 丹? 穿成那样
Why'd we do it, Dan? Dress up like that?
因为没有别人会做
No one else would.
是啊 你还记得我的制服吗?
Yeah, but do you remember my costume?
那身紧身胶衣 我说 太糟糕了
All that tight latex? I mean, it was awful.
啊 是啊 糟糕
Uh... Yeah, yeah, awful.
但我不想让妈妈失望
But didn't wanna disappoint Mother.
她希望我像她一样 打击坏人
Wanted her little girl to be just like her and fight bad guys.
我觉得"基恩法案"是我们遇到的最好的事情了
I think the Keene Act was the best thing that ever happened to us.
总之能让我们活得长久些
Well, we'll live longer anyway.
怎么了?
What?
乔恩认为 除非他做点什么…
Jon thinks, unless he can do something about it, that...
否则会有一场核战争
...there's gonna be nuclear war.
很快
Soon.
但我不知道该怎么想 我是说…
But I don't know what to think. I mean, it's all...
他的世界都是量子力学、平行现实之类的
...quantum mechanics and parallel realities with him.
我从不了解他实际看到的宇宙
I never even know what universe he's actually seeing.
他不停地离我远去…
He just keeps getting further away from me.
和其他人也一样
Everyone.
我甚至不能确定他是否还在乎我…
I can't even tell if he actually cares about me anymore...
还是说只是在假装
...or if he's just pretending.
如果他在假装 那说明他还在乎
If he's pretending, it means he cares.
等等 我给你开门
Hold on, I'll get the door.
谢谢 丹
Thanks, Dan.
- 坐好了?  - 对
- Got it? - Yeah.
你吃晚餐总是有政府护卫吗?
You always get a government escort to dinner?
他们是要确保我不会做出一些...
They're making sure I don't do anything to
让全国最强大的武器伤心的事情
upset the country's most powerful weapon.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我约你出来吃饭 叙旧 说笑…
I invite you out to dinner to catch up and have a few laughs...
但似乎那些日子并没有多少欢笑
...but there don't seem to be many laughs around these days.
还能期待些什么呢? 笑匠都死了
What do you expect? The Comedian's dead.
(棕榈泉报：苏联提高核弹头产量)
劳瑞 是你吗?
Laurie? Is that you?
还以为你应该已经习惯这种旅行方式了
Thought you'd be used to traveling that way by now.
我不习惯 我讨厌乔恩传送我
Well, I'm not. I hate it when Jon teleports me.
那也比经济舱强
Well, it beats flying coach.
来点玛格丽塔?
Margarita?
母亲 现在是下午2点
Mother, it's 2:00 in the afternoon.
嗯
Mm.
还记得那个一直给我写信的家伙吗?
Remember that guy that writes me letters?
他寄给我一件纪念品 是一本提瓦纳圣经
He sent me an item of memorabilia. It's a Tijuana bible.
三四十年代流行的8页色情漫画
This little eight-page porno comic they did in the '30s and '40s.
他寄给你这个?
He sent you this?
是啊 这很值钱的 算是古董了
Sure. They're very valuable, like antiques.
母亲 这东西太恶心了
Mother, this is gross.
我倒觉得这是某种恭维
I think it's kind of flattering.
为什么你生气的时候总是叫我"母亲"
Why do you always call me Mother when you're mad?
我知道你为什么来 我还能认字 知道吗?
I know why you're here. I can still read, you know.
我在报纸看到了
I saw it in the paper.
艾迪·布雷克的葬礼就在今天
Eddie Blake's funeral is today.
这就是他最后的笑点了 我想
Finally got his punchline, I guess.
可怜的艾迪
Poor Eddie.
可怜的艾迪? 他都那样对你了
Poor Eddie? After what he did to you?
噢 劳瑞 你还年轻
Oh, Laurie, you're still young.
你不了解
You don't know.
世事无常
Things change.
无论发生了什么 都是40年前的事了
What happened happened 40 years ago.
我已经67岁了
I'm 67 years old.
每一天 未来都变得暗淡
Every day, the future looks a little bit darker.
但是过去…
But the past...
即使是最肮脏的部分…
...even the grimy parts of it...
也越来越明亮
...keep on getting brighter.
我眼睛被闪到了
I've got spots in my eyes.
别这样 艾迪
Stop it, Eddie.
- 谢谢了 维基 - 谢谢 夜枭先生
- Thank you, Weegee. - Thank you, Mr. Owl.
明天 3点 我的工作室
Tomorrow, 3:00, my studio.
- 在第21街的一个小地方 - 听起来不错
- Little place on 21 st. - Sounds good.
哇 我们的合影 不知道我的头发看着怎么样
SALLY: Wow, a real photo session. Wonder how my hair will look?
噢 你先走吧 我5分钟就好
Oh, go ahead. I'll be there in five.
艾迪
Eddie.
你在这里干什么? 你知道我在换衣服
What the hell are you doing here? You knew I was changing.
我当然知道
Sure I did.
来吧 宝贝
Come on, baby.
我知道你需要什么
I know what you need.
你穿这么一套衣服 肯定有某些原因的
You gotta have some kind of reason for dressing in an outfit like this.
我说不要 艾迪
I said no, Eddie.
不要就是要
No spelled Y-E-S.
不要就是不要
No spelled N-O.
别这样
All right?
来吧 宝贝
Come on, sweetheart.
艾迪…
Eddie...
你个小畜生
You little bastard.
这就是你喜欢的?
This is what you like?
- 这样让你显得性感?  - 什么?
- This what makes you hot? - What?
世道艰难 到处都一样 甜心
Things are tough all over, cupcake.
雨水无分正义与不义 一视同仁
It rains on the just and the unjust alike.
笑匠有点亦正亦邪
The Comedian was a little bit of both.
而他一向认为自己是笑到最后的人
And he always thought he'd get the last laugh.
全知的主啊 我们内心的秘密
MAN: Thou knowest, Lord, the secrets of our hearts.
请用你那慈爱的耳 聆听我们的祷告…
Shut not thy merciful ears to our prayers...
宽恕我们吧 至圣之主 全能之主…
...but spare us, Lord most holy, O God most mighty...
噢 神圣而仁慈的主
...O holy and merciful savior.
你那最可畏惧的永恒审判
Thou most worthy judge eternal.
在我们生命的最后时刻 请不要让痛苦降临
Suffer us not at our last hour for any...
烟花 你跟我逗乐呢
EDDIE: Fireworks. You gotta be kidding me.
你看 本以为这该死的国家已经受够了烟火
You know, you'd think this goddamn country had had enough fireworks.
知道吗 如果我们在越南输了…
You know, if we'd lost here in Vietnam...
我想我们会被逼疯的 你懂的 我们这个国家
...I think it might have driven us crazy. You know, as a country.
但我们没有输 多亏了你
But we didn't, thanks to you.
你话说得苦涩
You sound bitter.
我? 苦涩?
Me? Bitter?
操 并不 我认为是搞笑
Fuck, no. I think it's hilarious.
噢 老天爷
Oh, Jesus Christ.
- 艾迪先生  - 来得真他妈是时候
- Mr. Eddie? - Just what I fucking needed.
战争结束了 我们必须谈谈这个孩子
The war is over now. We must talk about this baby.
没什么可谈的 瞧 我要离开了
There's nothing to talk about. See, I'm leaving.
我会把你忘掉的…
I'm gonna forget about you...
连同你这令人讨厌、湿热、一坨烂屎样的国家
...and your horrible, sweaty, little piece-of-shit country.
他妈的滚出去
Get the fuck out of here.
- 不  - 给我滚开
- No. - Get the fuck out of here.
你会记得的
You will remember.
你会记得我和我的国家…
You will remember me and my country...
永远记得
...forever!
我的脸
My face!
布雷克 不
Blake. Don't.
布雷克！
Blake!
她怀着孩子…
She was pregnant...
但你却枪杀了她
...and you gunned her down.
没错
That's right...
你知道吗? 你看着我干的
...and you know what? You watched me.
你本可以把我的枪变成蒸汽 子弹化成水银…
You could have turned the gun to steam, the bullets to mercury...
把那酒瓶变成该死的雪花片 但你没有这么做 不是吗?
...the bottle into goddamn snowflakes, but you didn't, did you?
你根本不在乎人类
You really don't give a damn about human beings.
你越来越脱离人性了 博士
You're drifting out of touch, doc.
愿上帝保佑我们
God help us all.
医务人员
Medic!
他来了又去 如同花开花谢
He cometh up and is cut down, like a flower.
在生命之中途 我们遭遇死亡
In the midst of life, we are in death.
除了你 我们还能往何处寻求援助 我的主啊
Of whom may we seek succor, but of thee, O Lord?
欢迎 我们很快开始
Welcome. We'll be starting shortly.
我们还在等一个人
We're waiting for one more.
我说过 你不是这里唯一精心装扮的人
I told you, you wouldn't be the only one dressed up.
欢迎你 博士
Welcome, doctor.
现在可以开始了
Now we can start.
感谢你们今天到来
Thank you for coming today.
我已经让你们提前熟悉这张罪案高发区地图
I asked you to acquaint yourselves with this map of high-crime areas.
(苏联称曼哈顿博士为"帝国主义者的武器")
这全是胡扯
This is all bullshit.
你知道吗 作为一个自称笑匠的人
You know, for a guy who calls himself the Comedian
我一直分不清你什么时候是在开玩笑
I can never tell when you're joking.
守望者 这才是真正的笑话
Watchmen. That's the real joke.
15年前就没起作用 现在也不会有用
It didn't work 15 years ago, and it ain't gonna work now...
就算你们想玩牛仔和印第安人的游戏
...because you wanna play cowboys and Indians.
或许我们应该同意开会时不能喝酒
Maybe we should agree on no drinking at meetings.
罗夏和我联手 已经在黑帮问题上取得进展
Rorschach and I have made headway on the gang problem by working together.
这么大个团队 看着像是作秀
A group this size seems like a publicity stunt.
我可不蹚这趟浑水
I'm not in it for the ink.
我们能做的有很多
ADRIAN: We can do so much more.
我们可以拯救这个世界
We can save this world...
- 如果有正确的领导  - 是啊
...with the right leadership. - Yeah.
那就是你喽 对吧 奥兹?
And that'd be you, right, Ozzy?
我是说 见鬼 你可是地球上最聪明的人
I mean, hell, you're the smartest man on the planet.
不需要天才也能看得出这世界有问题
It doesn't take a genius to see the world has problems.
对 但需要一屋子的蠢人
Yeah, but it takes a room of morons
自以为问题不大 他们能搞定
to think they're small enough for you to handle.
你们这帮人
You people.
听说摩罗神回到城里了 就开始小题大做
You hear Moloch's back in town, get your panties all in a bunch.
你们认为抓住他很重要?
You think catching him matters?
正义很重要
Justice matters.
正义
Justice.
正义就要伸张到我们头上来了
Justice is coming to all of us.
不管我们他妈的做什么
No matter what the fuck we do.
你知道吗 人类有史以来就不断地自相残杀
You know, mankind's been trying to kill each other off since the beginning of time.
而现在 人类终于有足够的能力相互毁灭了
Now we finally have the power to finish the job.
一旦那些核弹起飞 就什么事都不重要了
Ain't nothing gonna matter once those nukes start flying.
我们全都要成灰了
We'll all be dust.
然后这位法老王…
Then Ozymandias here...
就会是废墟上最聪明的人
...will be the smartest man on the cinder.
全能的上帝…
MAN: For as much as it hath pleased...
一视同仁地接纳我们已故兄弟的灵魂…
...almighty God to take onto himself the soul of our dear departed brother...
让我们就此把他的身体埋藏吧
...let us therefore commit his body to the ground.
土归土 尘归尘
Earth to earth, ashes to ashes...
(警察们说"让他们去干去")
(要警徽 不要面具)
我们要警察! 让警察保护人民!
Police! Police to protect the people!
请注意 市民们 我们正在努力维持秩序
DAN: Attention, citizens. We are trying to maintain order.
你们必须离开街头 直到警察罢工结束
You must clear the streets until the police strike is over.
请大家… 没有必要使用暴力
If you could... Please, there's no need for violence.
我们是来恢复街头秩序的 直到警察罢工结束
We are trying to retain order on the streets until the police strike is over.
爬回你们的洞穴 免得受伤
Crawl back in your holes before you get hurt.
- 我有橡胶子弹 - 我们有自己的权利
- I got rubber bullets. MAN 1: I want my rights!
- 你们不是法律！ - 我们要正常警察！
- You are not the law! MAN 2: We want regular cops!
不需要义警！
No more vigilantes!
我儿子就是警察 你个死基佬
My son's a police officer, you fucking faggots!
该死的 好吧 你们想这么做吗?
Goddamn it. All right. That's how you wanna do it?
没有必要使用暴力
There's no need for violence.
去你的！去你的！
Fuck you. Fuck you!
噢 事情闹大了
Oh, this is getting heavy.
天哪 我爱死在美国本土工作了 丹
Goddamn, I love working on American soil, Dan.
自从伍德沃德和伯恩斯坦后就没这么好玩过了
Ain't had this much fun since Woodward and Bernstein.
(水门事件的两个记者)
这样我们能维持多久?
How long can we keep this up?
国会正在推行一些新法案 把蒙面列为非法
Congress is pushing through some new bill that's gonna outlaw masks.
我们的日子不多了
Our days are numbered.
但在那之前 就像你常说的
Until then, it's like you always say:
"我们是社会唯一的保障"
We're society's only protection.
保护什么?
From what?
你说笑呢吧? 保护他们不被自己伤害
Are you kidding me? From themselves.
- 婊子养的  - 不 笑匠 等等！
- Son of a bitch. DAN: No, Comedian, wait!
把你的臭手拿开
Get your stinking hands off me.
我们这是怎么了?
What the hell happened to us?
美国梦去哪里了?
What happened to the American dream?
它成真了啊
It came true!
你看到的就是
You're looking at it.
(帐户已过期)
(金字塔跨国公司)
(纽约公报：苏联不会容忍美国在阿富汗的冒险行为)
(在你身后)
埃德加·威廉·雅各比
Edgar William Jacobi.
又称埃德加·威廉·沃恩 也就是"摩罗神"
Also known as Edgar William Vaughn. Also known as Moloch.
我不知道你说什么
What are you talking about?
我只是一个退休的商人
I'm a retired businessman...
再说谎 摩罗神 我就折断另一根指头
Lie again, Moloch, I break another finger.
我服过刑了
I did my time.
我不再是摩罗神了
I'm not Moloch anymore.
你想从我这里知道什么?
What do you want from me?
听说你参加了布雷克的葬礼 为什么?
Heard you attended Blake's funeral. Why?
我只是觉得我应该…
I just felt I should...
向笑匠表示敬意
...pay my respects to the Comedian.
你怎么知道他是笑匠?
How'd you know he was the Comedian?
他闯进了这里 一周前
He broke in here. A week ago.
他脱下了自己的面具
He had his mask off.
他喝醉了
He was drunk.
作为敌人几十年了
Enemies. For decades.
- 他为什么要拜访你?  - 我不知道
- Why should he visit you? - I don't know.
我在卧室里醒来 他就在我面前了
I woke up in my bedroom and there he was.
他很难过
He was upset.
他在哭
He was crying.
哭? 笑匠?
Crying? The Comedian?
他喃喃自语 没有意义的话
EDGAR: He was babbling, not making any sense.
我都吓尿了
I was pissing in my pants.
我以为他要杀我
I thought he was gonna kill me.
他说了什么?
RORSCHACH: What did he say?
就是个笑话
It's a joke.
全都是他妈的笑话
It's all a fucking joke.
你知道吗 我以为我了解
You know, I thought I knew how it was.
我以为我了解这世界
I thought I knew how the world was.
我做过些坏事
I've done some bad things.
我对女人做过坏事 我枪杀过孩子
I did bad things to women. I shot kids.
你知道的 在越南
In 'Nam, you know.
但那他妈是战争啊
But that was fucking war.
但是这次…
This...
我从没做过这样的事
I never done anything like this.
天 我在这里…
God, here I am...
在我最大的敌人面前…吐露心声
...spilling my guts...to one of my archenemies.
但事实是…
But the truth is...
你是我最接近于朋友的人了
...you're the closest thing to a friend I got.
这他妈说明了什么?
What the fuck does that say?
该死的
Shit.
你的名字…
And your name...
你的名字也在名单上…
...your name was on the list...
还有珍妮 不管她姓什么
...along with Janey, you know, whatever the fuck her name is.
曼哈顿的前女友
Manhattan's old girl.
母亲 原谅我
Mother, forgive me.
然后他就走了
EDGAR: And then he left.
我发誓我不知道他在说什么鬼话
I swear I don't know what the hell he was talking about.
有趣的故事
Funny story.
听着难以置信
Sounds unbelievable.
大概是真的
Probably true.
就这样?
So that's it?
我清白了?
I'm clean?
你?
You?
清白?
Clean?
苦杏仁苷
Amygdalin.
这种假药是从杏果核里提炼的
This phony medication made from apricot pits.
是不合法的
It's illegal.
求你了
Come on.
请别没收这个
Please don't confiscate that.
我在尝试各种办法
I'm trying anything.
我有癌症
I have cancer.
哪种癌?
What kind of cancer?
你知道最后会痊愈的那种吗?
You know the kind you eventually get better from?
我得的不是那种
That ain't the kind I got.
罗夏日记 10月16日
Rorschach's journal. October 16th.
想尝尝吗? 50块 我给你口交
Want some of this? Fifty bucks, I'll suck your cock.
- 回想着摩罗神说的故事 - 来吧
- Thought about Moloch's story. - Come on.
可能全是谎话
Could all be lies.
一个在坐牢期间策划的复仇计划
A revenge scheme planned during his years behind bars.
去你妈的
Fuck you.
我一个星期赚的比你一年都多 该死的基佬
I make more in a week than you make in a year, you fucking homo.
但如果是真的…
But if it's true...
有什么东西会吓得笑匠在摩罗神面前哭?
... what could have possibly scared the Comedian enough to cry in front of Moloch?
(尼克松：再来四年！)
他看到了什么?
What was it he saw?
还有他提到的名单
And that list he mentioned.
艾德华·布雷克 笑匠
Edward Blake. The Comedian.
生于1918年
Born 1918.
埋葬于雨中
Buried in the rain.
被谋杀
Murdered.
这就是我们的下场吗?
Is that what happens to us?
没时间交朋友?
No time for friends?
只有我们的敌人留下玫瑰
Only our enemies leave roses.
暴力的人生以暴力终结
Violent lives ending violently.
布雷克早就明白 人类的天性是野蛮的
Blake understood. Humans are savage in nature.
不管你怎样努力去装扮它…
No matter how much you try to dress it up...
掩饰它…
... to disguise it...
布雷克看见了社会的真面目
... Blake saw society's true face.
选择了去戏仿它 一个笑话
Chose to be a parody of it. A joke.
我听过一个笑话
I heard joke once.
一个男人去看医生 说他很沮丧
Man goes to doctor, says he's depressed.
人生看起来严酷而又残忍
Life seems harsh and cruel.
说他在这个充满威胁的世界上感觉孤独一人
Says he feels all alone in threatening world.
医生说疗法很简单
Doctor says treatment is simple.
伟大的小丑帕格里亚齐来了 去看他的表演吧
"The great clown Pagliacci is in town. Go see him.
那样应该让你振作起来
That should pick you up. "
那男人突然泪流满面
Man bursts into tears.
"但是医生" 他说 "我就是帕格里亚齐"
"But doctor," he says. "I am Pagliacci."
不错的笑话
Good joke.
人人都笑了
Everybody laugh.
一串鼓点声
Roll on snare drum.
谢幕
Curtains.
[片段2开始][目标][0:58:15.05][时长][0:02:17.08]
[片段2结束][目标][0:58:20.44][延迟][0:02:11.69]
你要在几点出席采访?
What time do you have to be at your interview?
别担心
JON: Don't worry.
我们有足够的时间
We've got plenty of time.
舔你的手指好像在舔电池
Your finger's like licking a battery.
天啊 乔恩 住手 你在干吗?
God, Jon, stop. What are you doing?
请不要生气
Please don't be upset.
我一直以为你喜欢这样
I always thought you liked this.
不！
LAURIE: No.
我不喜欢…不
I don't... No.
我不要这样
I don't want that.
我已经不知道该怎么让你兴奋起来了
I don't know what stimulates you anymore.
听着 我明白你在试着…
Look, I know you were just trying...
我们在床上的时候你还在工作?
Are you working in here while we're in bed together?
我和阿德里安的工作正处于重要的阶段
My work with Adrian is at a critical stage right now.
- 我觉得没有必要去… - 去做什么?
- I didn't think it was necessary to... - To what?
去通知我是哪个你在给我施舍性爱?
To what? To tell me which one of you is giving me a pity fuck?
我的注意力完全集中在你身上
My attention was completely focused on you.
如果你觉得我的态度有问题…
If you think there's a problem with my attitude...
我已经准备好和你讨论这点了
...I am prepared to discuss it.
你知道世间万物是如何组装的 除了人类
You know how everything in this world fits together except people.
我对你是什么? 又一个待解的谜题吗?
What am I to you? Another puzzle to be solved?
让你的人后退 我要把反应器传送到卡纳克神庙了
Have your men stand back. I'm teleporting the reactor to Karnak now.
你是我与这个世界的唯一存留的纽带
You're my only remaining link to the world.
我不想再背负这个责任了
I don't want that responsibility anymore.
(南极洲)
他归你了
He's all yours.
别担心 乔恩 她会回来的
ADRIAN: Don't worry, Jon. She'll be back.
不 她不会了
No, she won't.
他有很多称谓：英雄、武器…
MAN [ON TV]: He's been called many things: Hero, weapon...
国家安全的关键…
... linchpin of our national security...
核战争的威慑者 或者能毁灭世界的人
... deterrent to nuclear war, or a man to end worlds.
今夜稍晚 曼哈顿博士…
Later tonight, Dr. Manhattan...
会在一场独家采访中 回答我和大家的问题
... will answer my questions and yours in an exclusive interview...
将由维特企业毫无广告地为您送上
... brought to you commercial-free by Veidt Enterprises.
是谁?
Who is it?
是我 劳瑞
LAURIE: It's Laurie.
抱歉 我刚装了新门锁
Sorry. I just had this new lock installed.
我没其他地方可去
I didn't know where else to go.
哦 没关系 进来吧
Oh, it's okay. Come in.
怎么了?
What's wrong?
我离开乔恩了
I left Jon.
噢 天啊
Oh, God.
我很遗憾
I'm so sorry.
我不知道我干嘛来这里 我只是…
I don't know why I'm here. I just...
我不认识其他人
I don't know anybody else.
除了该死的超级英雄之外 我没有认识的人了
I don't know anybody except for goddamn superheroes.
没关系
That's okay.
你们大概只是吵嘴之类的
You probably just had an argument or something.
不是的 丹
No, Dan.
你不知道和他一起生活是什么样子
You don't know what it's been like living with him.
他看事物的方式 就好像他不…
The way he looks at things now, it's like he doesn't...
不记得它们是什么样子了
...remember what they are.
就好像这个世界 这个真实的世界…
It's like this world, this real world...
对他来说 就像是穿过迷雾
... to him, it's like walking through mist.
而人们只是一些影子
And people are just shadows.
雾中的影子
Shadows in a fog.
天啊 事情怎么会变得这么乱
God, how did everything get so tangled up?
很抱歉 丹
I'm sorry, Dan.
这是我第二次打搅了你的夜晚
This is twice now I've ruined your evening.
别这么说 我很高兴你来了
Come on. I'm glad you came over.
我正要去看霍利斯 进行每周的啤酒聚会
I was just gonna see Hollis for our weekly beer session.
我们很欢迎你加入
You're more than welcome to join.
实际上 我坚持你加入
In fact, I insist.
好极了 曼哈顿博士来了也没人通知我一声
Terrific. Dr. Manhattan arrives and no one thinks to tell me.
- 他刚刚… - 没时间化妆了
WOMAN: He just... - We don't have time for makeup.
这蓝光在电视里太亮了
That blue is too light for television.
这样够暗了吗?
Is that dark enough?
对 够暗了
PRODUCER: Yeah, that's dark enough.
(辐射庇护所)
世界的重量压在他身上 他会退缩吗? 不
BERNIE: The weight of the world's on him, but does he quit? No.
卖报纸的总是能解决 他们就像…
News vendors always cope. They're the...
噢 天啊 他又来了 那个流浪者
Oh, God, here comes that homeless guy again.
我说过了 这个月的一期还没有到
I told you, this month's issue still hasn't arrived yet.
你干嘛那么关心那些右派的破报纸?
Why do you care about that right-wing rag so much?
那帮混蛋根本不关心…
Those bastards don't give a damn.
慢着 他们送来了
Hold up. Here they come.
(新边际人报：荣耀如同雄鹰：有时蒙面是必要的)
- 西摩尔 - 伯尼 近来可好?
- Seymour. - Bernie, how's tricks?
不错 不错
BERNIE: Fine, fine.
看到我身后那个男人吗? 这周一直在烦我
See this guy behind me? Been bugging me all week.
或许我们该坐出租车 这里治安不好
Maybe we should get a cab. These are bad neighborhoods.
管它呢 正好我心情不爽
Yeah, well, I'm in a bad mood.
- 小妞 - 看看谁来了
MAN 1: Girl. MAN 2: What we got here?
这个是五角大楼开出的话题禁区清单
Here's a list of Pentagon-approved no-go areas.
他们一定会问起阿富汗的 一笔带过就好…
Afghanistan will obviously come up, but just play it cool...
还有别被逼进死胡同
...and try not to get into any tight corners.
一位著名的核子物理学家 在经过一场可怕的意外后…
- A renowned nuclear physicist, who, through a terrible accident...
被赋予了异乎寻常的力量 能够用意念操纵物质
...was gifted with extraordinary powers, capable of bending matter to his will.
今天 全世界都知道他的名字: 曼哈顿博士
Today, the world knows him as Dr. Manhattan.
欢迎你
Welcome.
谢谢
JON: Thank you.
这就对了
MAN 3: That's right.
布莱克女士 你来问第一个问题
Ms. Black, you have the first question.
曼哈顿博士 如你所知…
Dr. Manhattan, as you know...
"末日时钟"是用来象征性地…
...the Doomsday Clock is a symbolic clock face...
衡量人类距离灭绝时刻有多远
...analogizing humankind's proximity to extinction...
午夜代表着核战爆发的威胁
...midnight representing the threat of nuclear war.
而现在 它指向午夜前4分钟
As of now, it stands at four minutes to midnight.
你同意我们距离毁灭有那么近吗?
Would you agree that we're that close to annihilation?
我父亲以前是一个钟表匠
My father was a watchmaker.
在爱因斯坦发现时间是相对的之后 他就放弃了
He abandoned it when Einstein discovered that time is relative.
我只能说
I would only agree
一个象征性的钟表对于智者的营养
that a symbolic clock is as nourishing to the intellect...
就像一张氧气的照片之于溺水的人
...as a photograph of oxygen to a drowning man.
所以你是说没有危险?
So you're saying there is no danger.
即便在一个没有核武器的世界 依然有危险存在
JON: Even in a world without nuclear weapons, there would still be danger.
你会不会说 如同很多人说的那样…
MAN: And would you say, as so many claim...
你实际上就是"神"…
...that you are, in fact, a god...
鉴于你能够同时看到过去和未来?
...given that you see the past and future simultaneously?
我只能看到我自己的过去…
I can only see my own past...
…我自己的未来
... my own future.
我并不是全知的
I am not omniscient.
道格·罗斯 你的问题
KOPPEL: Doug Roth, your question?
说起你的过去 曼哈顿博士…
Speaking of your past, Dr. Manhattan...
你还记得一个叫沃利·维沃的男人吗?
...do you remember a man named Wally Weaver?
是的 我们在吉拉·弗莱茨研究基地共事过
Yes. We were both physicists together at the Gila Flats Research Base.
他死于癌症
He died of cancer.
- 他是一个好人 - 那么埃德加·雅各比呢?
- He was a good man. ROTH: How about Edgar Jacobi...
也就是被称作"摩罗神"的超级恶棍
... also known as the supervillain Moloch?
你和他在60年代的战斗、冲突中相遇过几次
You encountered him several times in the '60s: Battles, conflicts.
你知道他也得了癌症吗?
Did you know that he has cancer as well?
我并未被告知
I wasn't told.
那么安东尼·兰道夫将军呢?
ROTH: And what about General Anthony Randolph?
他是你在为政府工作时的联系人
He was your handler when you first started working for the government.
也是癌症
Cancer.
你在暗示我是诱因?
You're suggesting I was the cause.
就我来看 结论看起来毋庸置疑
ROTH: From where I'm standing, it's starting to look pretty conclusive.
即便真是这样 也无关紧要
JON: Even if that's the case, it's irrelevant.
一个活着的人体和一个死去的人体…
A live human body and a deceased human body...
具有相同数目的粒子
... have the same number of particles.
从结构上说 没有区别
Structurally, there's no difference.
好了 请安静一下
All right. Let's settle down, please.
那么珍妮·斯莱特呢?
What about Janey Slater?
你觉得她也无关紧要吗?
You think it makes a difference to her?
珍妮?
Janey?
你的前女友
ROTH: Your ex-girlfriend?
她也曾是个物理学家 你们交往了11年
She was a physicist too. You saw each other for 11 years.
道格 一次问一个问题
Doug, one question at a time.
她也得了癌症 医生说她只有半年命
She has cancer as well. Doctors have given her six months.
我说的对吗 斯莱特女士?
Isn't that right, Miss Slater?
你曾是我的世界 乔恩
You were the world to me, Jon.
你曾是我全部的生命
You were my whole life.
还记得你说过多少次你爱我吗?
Do you remember how many times you said you loved me?
珍妮 没人告诉我
Janey, I wasn't told.
那次意外后我对你不离不弃 我给了你一切
I stuck by you after the accident. I gave you everything.
这就是你给我的回报吗?
This is how you repay me?
珍妮 没人告诉过我 我不知道这事
Janey, I wasn't told. I didn't know.
诅咒你 乔恩
Damn you, Jon.
愿上帝诅咒你
Goddamn you.
珍妮 等等
Janey, wait.
够了 本次采访结束 来人
- That's it. This interview is over. MAN: Get up there.
把相机都拿走 所有人后退
Get those cameras off. Everybody back off.
所有人后退 我需要支援 别再烦他
Everybody back off. I need some backup here. Leave him alone.
请你们大家 都走开…
Please, if everyone would just go away...
别再烦我…
...and leave me alone...
你愿意发表评论吗?
Do you care to comment?
我说过 别烦我！
I said, leave me alone!
老天爷
Jesus.
我们…
Us...
被打劫了
...getting mugged.
走吧
Let's go.
我在发抖
I'm shaking.
你知道吗?
You know what?
我累坏了 今晚就到这儿吧
I'm wiped. I'm just gonna call it a night.
噢 你真的不和我一起去霍利斯家…
Oh, are you sure you don't wanna come by Hollis' with me...
消化一下肾上腺素吗?
...and shake off the adrenaline?
我想我今晚已经受够了超级英雄的事了
LAURIE: I think I've had enough hero stuff for one night.
有你倾听帮了很大忙
It helped having you listen.
随时欢迎
DAN: Any time.
保重 丹
LAURIE: Take care, Dan.
这世道不太平
It's a rough world out there.
回见
DAN: Be seeing you.
[片段3开始][目标][1:10:54.40][时长][00:04:42.39]
[片段3结束][目标][1:10:54.40][延迟][00:04:42.39]
你来晚了
You're late.
啊 是的 是的
Ah, I know. I know.
你不会相信刚刚发生了什么
You won't believe what happened.
曼哈顿博士刚在电视直播中发飙了
Dr. Manhattan just lost it on live TV.
等等 什么?
Wait, what?
我刚和劳瑞一起 她不知道这事
I was just with Laurie. She doesn't know.
她很快就会知道了 全世界都会知道
HOLLIS: She's gonna know soon enough. The whole world will know.
我说了 别烦我！
I said, leave me alone!
我看着星空
JON: I am looking at the stars.
它们是那么遥远…
They're so far away...
它们的光芒要那么久才能到我们这里…
... and their light takes so long to reach us...
我们看到的星星都只是它们的旧照片
... all we ever see of stars are their old photographs.
在1959年7月 我恋爱了
It is July, 1959, and I am in love.
好极了
MAN: That's great.
- 你明天来取相片 - 好的
- You can pick it up tomorrow. - Okay.
- 75美分 - 好 谢谢你
- Seventy-five cents. - Okay, thank you.
谢谢
Thank you.
天啊 乔恩 希望他刚才给我们一点提示
Gosh, Jon, I wish he gave us a little notice.
我肯定做了怪表情
I'm sure I made a face.
噢 不会 我保证你样子很好看
Oh, no, no. I'm sure that you'll look beautiful.
她的名字是珍妮·斯莱特
Her name is Janey Slater.
她是一个物理学家 和我一样
She is a physicist, like me.
我30岁
I am 30 years old.
她是我大学好友沃利·维勒介绍认识的
We were introduced by a good friend of mine from college, Wally Weaver.
在1981年2月12日
It is February 12th, 1981.
沃利死于癌症 他们现在说是我导致的
Wally dies of cancer, of which they now say I am the cause.
那一晚 珍妮和我第一次做爱
That night, Janey and I make love for the first time.
一个月之后 那场意外在等着我
A month from now, the accident awaits me.
噢 我一会儿赶上你们
Oh, I'll catch up with you guys.
我好像把手表留在了里面
I think I left my watch inside.
嘿 我们等等他吧
Hey. Let's just wait a second.
我穿过房间来到本征场中心 找到我的手表
I cross the room to the Intrinsic Field Center. I find my watch.
当我走到门前时…
When I get to the door...
沃利脸色都白了
... Wally is turning white.
程序被锁死了 我们没法解除时间锁
The program's locked in. We can't override the time lock.
我被吓坏了
I am terrified.
乔恩?
JANEY: Jon?
对不起 乔恩…
I'm sorry, Jon...
我不能眼睁睁看着…
...but I can't...
珍妮 别离开我！
Janey, don't leave me!
别离开我！
Don't leave me!
那是1959年5月12日 我被介绍给珍妮的时候
It is May 12th, 1959, when I'm introduced to Janey.
她给我买了杯啤酒…
She buys me a beer...
那是第一次有女人为我做这样的事
... the first time a woman has done this for me.
当她递给我那冰冷、溢满的酒杯时…
As she passes me the cold, perspiring glass...
我们的手指相碰了
... our fingers touch.
对 乔恩 不错
Yes, Jon, good.
现在的问题只是 按照正确的顺序重新组装这些零件
Now it's just a question of reassembling the components in the correct sequence.
那是我最后一次…
I feel fear...
感受到恐惧
... for the last time.
举行了一次象征性的葬礼
A token funeral is held.
没有东西可以埋葬
There is nothing to bury.
珍妮把那张照片装裱了起来
Janey frames the snapshot.
那是我在世上唯一的一张照片
It's the only photograph of me anyone has.
有人在墙外看到了一副人体循环系统
A circulatory system is seen by the perimeter fence.
几天后…
A few days later...
一具覆盖了部分肌肉的人体骨骼站在走廊上
... a partially muscled skeleton stands in a hallway...
在它消失之前 还尖叫了一阵
... and screams for a moment before vanishing.
噢 上帝
Oh, God.
乔恩?
Jon?
是你吗?
Is that you?
世界各国对今天上午的声明感到震惊…
Nations around the world reeling from this morning's announcement...
可能是当代历史上最重大的事件
...possibly the most significant event in recent history.
我重复一次 超人存在 而且他是个美国人
We repeat, the superman exists, and he is American.
他们叫我曼哈顿博士…
They call me Dr. Manhattan.
他们解释说选这个名字…
They explain the name has been chosen...
是为了让美国的敌人们产生不安的联想
... for the ominous associations it will raise in America's enemies.
宣传部的伙计们说我需要一个标志
The marketing boys say I need a logo.
如果我非要有个象征…
If I'm to have a symbol...
那就应该是我所敬仰的
... it shall be one I respect.
他们把我打造成某种俗艳的…
They are shaping me into something gaudy...
致命的东西
... something lethal.
在1971年1月…
In January, 1971...
尼克松总统要我干涉越战…
... President Nixon asks me to intervene in Vietnam...
一件他的前任不会要求我干的事
... something that his predecessors would not ask.
一周之后 冲突结束了
A week later, the conflict ends.
一些越共士兵想要向我个人投降
Some of the Vietcong forces wanna surrender to me personally.
霍利斯·梅森 一位退休的变装英雄 写了本书
Hollis Mason, a retired costume hero, writes a book.
书里 他把我的到来称为超级英雄的黎明
In it, he calls my arrival the dawn of the superhero.
我不确定我是否明白这句话的意思
I am not sure if I know what that means.
你看 当时 我被错误引用了
WALLY: You see, at the time, I was misquoted.
我从未说过："超人存在 而且他是美国人"
I never said, "The superman exists and he is American."
我当时说的是："上帝存在 而且他是美国人"
What I said was, "God exists, and he is American."
好了 如果你开始对这个概念…
Now, if you begin to feel an intense...
有一种极为糟糕的宗教恐怖的感觉
...and crushing feeling of religious terror at the concept...
不要担心
...don't be alarmed.
那说明你们的头脑依然清醒
That indicates only that you are still sane.
那是1963年的圣诞节
It is Christmas, 1963.
珍妮告诉我说她害怕 而且担心
Janey tells me she is afraid, and worried.
她说我现在就像一个神
She says I am like a god now.
我告诉她 我认为没有神
I tell her I don't think there is a God.
如果真的有 我也一点都不像他
And if there is, I'm nothing like him.
我告诉她我依然想要她…
I tell her I still want her...
而且会永远想要她
... and that I always will.
我向她说了谎 在1970年9月4日
As I lie to her, it is September 4th, 1970.
我在一个人们全穿着蒙面制服的房间里
I am in a room full of people wearing disguises.
一个很年轻的女孩对着我笑
A very young girl looks at me and smiles.
她很美
She's beautiful.
每次长吻后 她会在我唇上留下一个的温柔的小吻…
After each long kiss, she plants a smaller, gentler one upon my lips...
就像是一个签名
... like a signature.
珍妮指责我追逐未成年女
Janey accuses me of chasing jailbait.
她爆发出愤怒的泪水
She bursts into angry tears,
问我是不是因为她变老了
asking if it's because she's getting older.
是真的
It's true.
她每天都在明显地老去
She's aging more noticeably every day...
而我却一直不变
... while I am standing still.
我更喜欢这里的宁静不变
I prefer the stillness here.
我厌倦了地球
I am tired of Earth.
这些人
These people.
我厌倦了被困在他们的生命纠葛中
I'm tired of being caught in the tangle of their lives.
他们声称自己的劳作是在打造天堂…
They claim their labors are to build a heaven...
但他们的天堂充满着恐惧
... yet their heaven is populated with horrors.
或许世界不是被制造出来的
Perhaps the world is not made.
或许万物都不是制造出来的
Perhaps nothing is made.
就像没有工匠的钟表
A clock without a craftsman.
太晚了
It's too late.
从来都是…
Always has been...
永远都是…太晚了
... always will be too late.
而你不知道他会去哪里?
FORBES: And you have no idea where he would've gone.
我怎么会知道?
LAURIE: How would I know?
大概是在世界的另一端研究分子
Probably on the other side of the world studying molecules.
我们的卫星已经对地球作了一次扫描
FORBES: Our satellites have done a sweep of the planet.
哪里都没有他能量信号的迹象
There's no trace of his energy signature anywhere.
真的?
Really?
朱庇特小姐 今天你和曼哈顿博士吵架了吗?
Miss Jupiter, did you and Dr. Manhattan have a fight today?
这他妈不关你的事
None of your fucking business.
当你拿政府的薪水但却没干活的时候 就关我的事了
It is when you're on government payroll and you're not doing your job.
你说的话就相当于叫我"妓女" 佛布斯探员
That's as close to the word "whore" as you're gonna get with me, Agent Forbes.
抽烟吗?
Smoke?
我道歉 朱庇特小姐
My apologies, Miss Jupiter.
你了解曼哈顿博士对于我们的国家安全有多重要
You know how important Dr. Manhattan is to our national security.
你能想象到我们的担忧
You can imagine our concern.
我只能想象…
I can only imagine.
一旦那些核弹起飞 就什么事都不重要了 我们全都要成灰了
EDDIE: Ain't nothing gonna matter once those nukes start flying. We'll all be dust.
而后这位法老王…
Then Ozymandias here...
将会是废墟里最聪明的人
...will be the smartest man on the cinder.
劳瑞? 劳瑞·简?
EDDIE: Laurel? Laurel Jane?
你是沙莉·朱庇特的女儿
You're Sally Jupiter's kid.
你是笑匠 对吧?
You're the Comedian, right?
你刚才很酷
You were pretty cool in there.
知道吗? 你妈妈她以前是历史选美冠军
You know, your mom, she was one of the all-time champion beauties.
你遗传了她的眼睛 甚至眼角那颗痣也一样
You got her eyes, you know. You even have that same funny little mole.
把你的手拿开
Take your hands off her.
嘿 美人 好久不见
Hey, doll. Long time no see.
对我来说还不够久 埃迪
Not long enough in my book, Eddie.
上车
Get in the car.
你的沉沦完全没有底线吗?
Are there no depths you won't sink to?
老天 莎莉 一个人就不能和他的…
Jesus Christ, Sally. Can't a guy talk to his...
老友的女儿说话?
...you know, old friend's daughter?
我说 你以为我是什么人?
I mean, what the hell do you think I am?
我们找到他了
MAN: We found him!
- 找到他了 - 他在哪儿?
- We found him. FORBES: Where is he?
火星
Mars.
总统先生…
Mr. President...
苏联军队已经把坦克开到阿富汗边境
...the Soviets have moved their tanks just short of the Afghan border.
他们在试探我们…
They are testing us...
看我们是否捏造了曼哈顿博士的失踪…
...to see if we manufactured Dr. Manhattan's disappearance...
由此引诱他们出击
...to coax a move out of them.
如果他们意识到这不是骗局
GENERAL 1: If they realize it's not a hoax,
他们大概会开始发动空袭
they'll probably start with air strikes.
如果他们做了 几天内就能控制阿富汗
If they do, they'll have Afghanistan under control in a matter of days.
核科学家监督组已经把"末日时钟"拨到…
A watchdog group of nuclear scientists has moved the Doomsday Clock...
午夜前2分钟
...to two minutes until midnight.
把这破玩意撤下屏幕
NIXON: Get this shit off the screen.
这些混蛋算老几 来说末日临近时间?
Who are these assholes to say when doomsday approaches?
末日临近时间由我来说了算
I say when doomsday is approaching.
那么
Now, then.
华沙条约的其他成员国呢?
What about the rest of the Warsaw Pact countries?
捷克斯洛伐克、波兰和东德 已经动员他们的部队
Czechoslovakia, Poland and East Germany have mobilized their forces.
但是还没有动作 他们在玩"等等看"
But no movement yet. They're playing a wait-and-see.
让苏联领头
Letting the Russians take the lead.
大胆行动 亨利 这才是我们现在需要的
Bold moves, Henry. That's what's needed right now.
不能让这些混蛋觉得我们软弱
We can't let these fuckers think we're weak.
是啊 他们一定怕"疯子理查德·尼克松"
Yes. They must fear the madman Richard Nixon.
要多久我们才能准备好先发攻击?
How soon can we be ready for a preemptive strike?
两天之后
Two days.
我们有54%的几率在他们的导弹升空之前…
We have a 54 percent chance of wiping out the entire U.S.S.R...
扫平整个苏联
...before they get their missiles airborne.
我们的损失会是什么?
What would our losses be?
保守地估算…
Assuming conservative projections...
我们能预先摧毁多少苏维埃核弹头
...of how many Soviet warheads are destroyed beforehand...
我们会失去东海岸的全部
...we'll lose all of the East Coast.
这将是…哈佛校园最后的喘息了
The last gasp...of the Harvard establishment.
让我们看看他们怎么用脑子对付核裂变
Let's see them think their way out of fission.
根据预期风向模型 辐射云会飘往南方
With anticipated wind patterns, the fallout drift would head south.
墨西哥会遭受最坏结果
Mexico would catch the worst of it.
大部分美国农业区可能不会受影响
Most of the farm belt might remain unaffected.
不算太糟…
Not so bad...
全面考虑下来
...all things considered.
总统先生…
GENERAL 2: Mr. President...
你打算怎么做?
...what would you like to do?
把我们的戒备状态升到2级
Take us to DEFCON two.
开始给导弹加燃料
Begin fueling the bombers.
曼哈顿博士有两天时间
Dr. Manhattan has two days.
那之后…
After that...
人类就掌握在比我更高层的人手里了
...humanity is in the hands of a higher authority than mine.
让我们希望他站在我们这边吧
Let's just hope he's on our side.
- 肯定有办法接近他的 - 打搅了
FORBES: There must be a way to reach him. LAURIE: Excuse me.
无线电广播、太空飞船
FORBES: Radio transmission, space shuttles...
- 打扰了 - 什么?
LAURIE: Excuse me. FORBES: What?
我要去趟洗手间
LAURIE: I need to use the restroom.
你还不明白吗?
Don't you understand?
能把乔恩带回来的人只有乔恩
The only thing that can bring Jon back is Jon.
如果他想找到我 他会的
If he wants to find me, he will.
我这一生当囚徒当够了
I've been a prisoner in my life long enough.
没有曼哈顿博士在这里…
MAN: Without Dr. Manhattan around...
恐吓苏联人维持和平 维特先生…
...to bully the Russians into peace, Mr. Veidt...
人们将会需要那些经典的老式能源
...people are going to need good, old-fashioned energy to rely on.
你能明白的
You can understand.
世界不能突然放弃使用石油和核能
The world can't just quit on oil and nuclear power cold turkey.
你会在一夜之间搞垮我们的整个经济
You'll dismantle our entire economy overnight.
你说得对 李
You're right, Lee.
为什么是免费能源?
And why free energy?
"免费"不过是"社会主义"的代名词
Well, "free" is just another word for "socialist."
我们也许不得不开展一项公开调查…
We might have to make a public inquiry...
查查你可能加入过什么共产团体
...into any past communist affiliations you might have had.
拉科卡先生 各位…
ADRIAN: Mr. Lacocca, gentlemen...
我尊重你们的立场…
...I respect your position...
还有你们作为业界首领的成就 我的确尊重
...and what you've accomplished as captains of industry. I do.
你们想了解我的过去 嗯?
You wanna know my past? Hm?
好 我很乐意
Okay. Happily.
这是公开的记录 我17岁时父母双亡…
It's a matter of public record that by 17, both my parents were dead...
留下我一人
...leaving me alone.
我想可以说 我一直是孤身一人
I guess you could say I've always been alone.
他们说我是这世上最聪明的人
They say I'm the smartest man in the world,
但真相是我时常觉得愚蠢…
but the truth is I've often felt stupid...
因为难以和他人建立关系
...at being unable to relate to anyone.
哦 我指的是活人
Well, anyone living, that is.
唯一让我感觉亲切的人…
The only person with whom I felt kinship...
在基督降世的300年前就死了
...died 300 years before the birth of Christ.
马其顿的亚历山大
Alexander of Macedonia
也就是你们熟知的 亚历山大大帝
or Alexander the Great, as you know him.
他对于联合世界的远见…
His vision of a united world was...
是史无前例的
Well, it was unprecedented.
我想要…
I wanted...
我需要…去匹配他的功绩…
...needed to match his accomplishments...
所以我立志在今日的世界践行古训
...so I resolved to apply antiquity's teachings to our world today.
于是开始了我的征服之路
And so began my path to conquest.
不是征服人类…
Conquest not of men...
而是征服那些困扰人类的邪恶
...but of the evils that beset them.
矿物燃料、原油、核能…
Fossil fuels, oil, nuclear power...
它们就像是毒品
...are like a drug
而你们各位 跟那些国外投资者 就是毒贩
and you, gentlmen, along with foreign interests are the pushers.
好了 听着
Now, listen.
不
ADRIAN: No.
你们听着
You listen.
这世界会幸存的…
The world will survive...
而且它配得到更多 远超过你们所能提供的
...and it deserves more than you've been able to provide.
所以让我们直说吧 好吧?
So let's cut to it, shall we?
私下里我的价值远超你们所有的公司的总和
Privately I'm worth more than all of your corporations combined.
我可以收购并出售你们三次
I could buy and sell you three times over,
你们在作决定时应该考虑这点
which is something you should factor into your decision...
你们是否应该选择…
...should you choose to make our...
把我们的分歧 公之于众
...disagreement public.
我想你们知道该怎么做了
I think you know the way out.
失陪了
Gentlemen.
玩具公司的人想和你讨论 法老王系列的新反派
The toy people wanna talk to you about new villains for the Ozymandias line.
老敌人好像都死光了
Seems all the old villains are dead
维特先生?
Mr. Veidt?
我想我有些主意
I think I have some ideas.
维特先生?
Mr. Veidt?
我觉得我们之前可能有点小误会
I think we got off on the wrong foot.
他嘴里有剧毒胶囊
He's got a poison capsule.
不准吞下去 你这混蛋！谁派你来的?
Don't bite down, you son of a bitch. Who sent you?
我要一个名字
I want a name.
把名字告诉我
Give me a name!
自杀胶囊
LAURIE: Suicide pill.
氰化钾 入口即死
Potassium cyanide. Guy was dead before he hit the ground.
谢谢 亲
WAITRESS: Thanks, hon.
那么罗夏说对了
Then Rorschach was right.
这不是个别案件
This wasn't some lone nut.
是一个组织
It's an organization:
资金充足 装备精良
Well-funded, well-equipped.
可是谁会想在这时候杀我们?
But who'd wanna kill us now?
我不知道 但是外面已经不安全了
I don't know, but it's not safe out here.
那个…没有乔恩的消息?
So no word from Jon?
没有
No.
你看…
Well, listen...
为什么你不过来和我一起住呢?
...why don't you come stay with me?
不了 你真好心 但我不想打扰
Oh, no. That's sweet, but I wouldn't wanna impose.
哦 不 就当帮我个忙好了
Oh, no. No. Think of it as doing me a favor.
这样我就不用担心你一人在外面了
I wouldn't have to worry about you being out there.
好吧
Okay.
罗夏日记 1985年10月21日
Rorschach's journal, October 21 st, 1985.
在第43街和第7街
On 43rd and 7th,
看见德雷伯格和朱庇特 吃完快餐出来
saw Dreiberg and Jupiter leaving diner.
我不戴面具他们就不认识我
They didn't know me without my mask.
外遇吗?
An affair?
是她伤了曼哈顿博士的心 促使他离开?
Did she break Manhattan's heart to engineer his exile...
从而给德雷伯格腾地方?
... to make room for Dreiberg?
曼哈顿到底有没有一颗会受伤的心呢?
Does Manhattan even have a heart to break?
小巷阴冷而又荒凉
The alley was cold, deserted.
我的东西就在原地 等着我
My things were where I left them, waiting for me.
我的大衣 我的鞋子 我一尘不染的手套
My coat, my shoes, my spotless gloves.
我的脸
My face.
穿上他们 我就卸下了伪装
Putting them on, I abandoned my disguise...
变回我自己
... became myself.
摆脱了恐惧和软弱
Free from fear or weakness...
还有欲念
... or lust.
小巷深处
Down alley...
听见女人尖叫
... heard woman scream.
城市夜间合唱团的第一个扬起的音符
First bubbling note of city's evening chorus.
意图强奸?
Attempted rape.
抢劫?
Mugging.
两样都是?
Both.
那人转过来
The man turned...
他的眼光里有一种奖赏
... and there was something rewarding in his eyes.
有时候夜晚对我很慷慨
Sometimes the night is generous to me.
去刺杀维特的是一个本地的底层人 名叫罗伊·切斯
Veidt's assassin was a local lowlife named Roy Chess.
在他的公寓里 我找到了线索
At his apartment, I found clues.
似乎他在金字塔跨国公司工作
Seems he worked at Pyramid Transnational.
我见过这个标志
I've seen the logo before...
在摩罗神家里
... at Moloch's.
摩罗神 今天有人想枪杀世界上最聪明的人
Someone tried to shoot the world's smartest man today, Moloch.
是个为金字塔跨国公司干活的人
Guy worked for Pyramid Transnational.
看来他们不只有送货服务
More than a just delivery service, I take it.
我上次来的时候
Last time I was here,
看见同一家公司签发的退休金支票
Last time I was here, I saw a pension check written from the same company.
我猜想这是个幌子公司
I'm guessing it's a front
是某个想要谋杀蒙面英雄的人开设的
set up by whoever wants us masks dead.
现在 别再撒谎了 摩罗神
Now, no more lies, Moloch.
谁在运营金字塔公司?
Who runs Pyramid?
罗夏
Rorschach.
我们是警察 我们知道你在里面
This is the police. We know you're in there.
不 不！
No. No!
如果有人和你在一起 请让他们安全地出来
If there's anybody in there with you, send them out unharmed.
不 不 不 不
No. No, no, no!
被陷害了 落入陷阱 愚蠢 愚蠢！
Framed. Walked right into it. Stupid, stupid, stupid!
永远 永远不投降
Never, never surrender.
好吧 我希望你已经准备好了 英雄
All right. I hope you're ready, hero.
随时奉陪
When you are.
一
One...
二
...two...
三
...three.
加把劲
Come on.
这个混蛋
MAN: Son of a bitch.
- 天 这家伙臭死了 - 把他的面具拿掉
- Christ, he stinks. - Get that mask off him.
- 拿下了 - 不 不！
- I got it. - No. No!
我的脸 把我的脸还给我
My face! Give me back my face!
蒙面义警罗夏已被逮捕
The masked vigilante Rorschach was apprehended...
确认身份是沃特·科瓦克斯 一位35岁的白人男性
... and identified as Walter Kovacs, a 35-year-old white male.
关于科瓦克斯所知不多
Little's known about Kovacs,
不过他已被控告谋杀埃德加·雅各比
but he was charged with the murder of Edgar Jacobi,
此人被发现在布朗克斯的家中头部中枪
found shot in the head in his home in the Bronx.
在艰难的抓捕过程中…
Police officers were injured and Jacobi's home was set ablaze...
多名警员受伤 雅各比的家被烧
... during the violent course of the capture.
罗夏
MAN 1: Rorschach!
我会像干你妈一样干死你
I'm gonna fuck you like I fucked your mother!
出来 罗夏
MAN 2: Come on out, Rorschach!
沃特·科瓦克斯
MAN: Walter Kovacs.
[片段4开始][目标][1:37:51.05][时长][00:02:55.96]
[片段4结束][目标][1:37:51.05][延迟][00:02:55.96]
这是你的真名? 沃特?
Is that your name? Walter?
让我解释一下你的处境 沃特
Well, let me explain your situation here, Walter.
你跟我合作
You cooperate with me...
我也许就能说服他们 给你应该的医疗救治
...and I may be able to convince them that you should be treated medically.
在一家医院 我相信那对你有好处
In a hospital. I believe that would be good for you.
可是当局想把你和普通犯人关在一起
But the authorities wanna put you with the general population.
- 监狱就是监狱  - 啊 没错
- Prison's a prison. - Uh-huh. Yes.
不过差别在于 在那里
But the difference is, down there...
你会被生吞活剥的
...you'd be eaten alive.
你导致这里很多人坐牢 沃特
You're responsible for a lot of them being in prison here, Walter.
告诉我你看见了什么
Tell me what you see.
(罗夏墨迹测试 通过抽象图像反映被测者的潜意识 是"罗夏"称号的由来)
一只漂亮的蝴蝶
A pretty butterfly.
现在呢? 你看见了什么?
What about now? What do you see here?
妈妈?
Mom?
他在伤害你吗?
Is he hurting you?
你他妈的还有个孩子
You got a fucking kid in here.
这个我家里就有
I get that at home.
杂种 我早应该堕胎的
Bastard. I should have had that abortion.
一些漂亮的花儿
Some nice flowers.
我听说这小子老妈是个妓女
BO Y 1: I heard this guy's mom's a whore.
你有没有从她那里染上什么病?
Did you catch any diseases from her?
有吗? 妓女的儿子?
Huh? Whoreson.
听我说 弱智
Listen to me, retard.
喂 你觉得她会不会为一美元给我吸屌?
BO Y 2: Hey, you think she'd suck my dick for a dollar?
云彩
Clouds.
跟我谈谈罗夏 你愿意吗 沃特?
Tell me about Rorschach. Will you do that, Walter?
你一直叫我沃特
You keep calling me Walter.
我不喜欢你
I don't like you.
你不喜欢我 好吧 具体是为什么呢?
You don't like me. All right, why is that, exactly?
你肥胖
You're fat.
有钱 自由派情感倾向
Wealthy. Liberal sensibilities.
你所谓的同情
What you call compassion.
想保护和理解那些犯罪
Wanting to protect and understand the guilty.
这个腐败的社会 把这叫做"康复"
This rotting society, what it calls rehabilitation.
完全就是一种妥协
Nothing short of compromise.
想让你变好也是一种妥协吗?
Is it a compromise to want to make you well?
这儿有其它人行为比我更极端 医生
There are other men in here with behavior more extreme than mine, doctor.
当然了 他们不够出名 对吧?
Of course, they're not famous, are they?
你想了解罗夏?
You wanna know about Rorschach?
我来跟你说说罗夏
I'll tell you about Rorschach.
一旦一个人看清了社会的黑色内里
Once a man has seen society's black underbelly...
他就再不能置之不理
...he can never turn his back on it.
再也不能假装 像你那样
Never pretend, like you do...
假装它不存在
...that it doesn't exist
不管有谁命令他转头别看
no matter who orders him to look the other way.
我们做这些…事情
We don't do this thing...
不是因为有许可
...because it's permitted.
而是因为不得不做
We do it because we have to.
是因为我们被迫去做
We do it because we're compelled.
那时候我正在调查一件绑架案
I was investigating a kidnap case.
布莱尔·罗奇
Blaire Roche.
6岁大的女孩
Six-year-old girl.
那时我还年轻
I was young then.
对罪犯太手软
Too soft on criminals.
我让他们活命
I let them live.
打断一个人的胳膊 得到线索
Broke a man's arm to get a tip.
指引我来到失踪女孩的位置
Led me to the missing girl's location.
我知道那女孩在这儿
I knew the girl was here...
不过我搜查那地方时什么也没看到
... but when I searched the place, I saw nothing.
然后我找到了她
And then I found her.
弗雷德
MAN: Fred.
巴尼
Barney.
谁给老爸叫两声?
Who's gonna bark for Daddy?
杀人犯回来的时候 天已经黑了
It was dark when the murderer got back.
一片漆黑
As dark as it gets.
老天 谁在外面? 是谁?
Oh, God. Who's out there? Who is it?
是谁?
Who is it?
什么? 他妈的怎么回事?  你他妈的是谁?
What? What the fuck? Who the fuck are you?
你他妈想怎么样?
What the fuck do you want?
你杀了我的狗 老兄
You killed my dogs, man!
你以为我和那个女孩有关?
You think I had something to do with that girl?
那是我捡来的
I found that.
你有什么证据? 那什么都不是
What evidence have you got? That's nothing.
好吧 我认罪
Okay. I confess.
我绑架了她 我杀了她
I kidnapped her. I killed her.
逮捕我吧
Arrest me.
怎么了? 逮捕我！
What? Arrest me!
是我干的 我说了是我干的
I did it! I said I did it!
老天哪！
Christ.
听着 我有问题 老兄
Look, I've got a problem, man.
把我送进去吧 我需要救助
Fucking take me in. I need help.
不 不要 别这样
No, don't. Don't do that.
把我关起来
Take me in.
不要啊 不
Don't! No!
人 被捕
Men get arrested.
狗受死
Dogs get put down.
我的手被震到麻痹
Tremors of impact shook my arm.
温暖的血液溅到我脸上
Warm blood splashed my face.
所有属于沃特·科瓦克斯的部分
Whatever was left of Walter Kovacs
都在那晚和那小姑娘一起死去了
died that night with that little girl.
从那时起 就只有罗夏
From then on, there was only Rorschach.
你看 医生 上帝并没有杀死那小女孩
See, doctor, God didn't kill that little girl.
命运并没有把她切块
Fate didn't butcher her
宿命也没有拿她喂那些狗
and destiny didn't feed her to those dogs.
如果上帝看见了那晚我和他所做的事
If God saw what any of us did that night,
那看来他并不在乎
he didn't seem to mind.
从那时起 我就明白
From then on, I knew:
上帝并没有把世界造成这样
God doesn't make the world this way.
是我们做的
We do.
我帮不了他
I can't help him.
嘿 罗夏
Hey, Rorschach.
嘿 你很有名 是吧?
Hey, you're pretty famous, right?
罗夏 我听说你妈是个妓女
MAN 1: Rorschach, I heard your mother was a whore.
你知道吗?
Hey, you know what?
我也挺出名的
I'm pretty famous too.
- 我说的对不对?  - 说得对
- Ain't that right?  MAN 2: That's right.
你看 也许我能给你签个名
You know, maybe I can give you an autograph.
你说怎么样 大人物?
What you say, big boy?
你们好像没搞明白
None of you seem to understand.
不是我被关在了你们这里
I'm not locked in here with you.
够了 住手
OFFICER: All right, that's it!
是你们被关在了我这里
You're locked in here with me.
劳瑞！
DAN: Laurie!
糟了
Shit.
- 撑住 - 妈的
DAN: Hold on. - Fuck.
我来 我来 我来
I got it, I got it, I got it.
真抱歉 我正在四处探索
I'm so sorry. I was snooping around
一定是按错了按钮
and I must have hit the wrong button.
你受伤了吗?
Are you hurt?
没有 我没事
No, no. Okay. I'm fine.
我感觉很抱歉
I just feel so bad.
没事 别担心
No, don't worry.
以前就发生过
It's happened before.
笑匠在77年就干过
Comedian did it back in '77.
阿奇逃过了那一劫
Archie survived that.
阿奇?
LAURIE: Archie?
呃 就是阿基米德的简称
Oh. Well, uh, short for Archimedes...
梅林 亚瑟王的法师 的宠物猫头鹰
...Merlin's pet owl.
愚蠢的外号
Stupid nickname.
你怎么买得起这些东西的?
LAURIE: How did you ever afford all this stuff, anyway?
哦 我爸之前在企业银行 后来…
Well, my dad was in corporate banking and...
他死后给我留下很多钱
left me a lot of money when he died...
这事一直让我惊讶 我是说 他以前…
...which always surprised me. I mean, he was...
我以为他很失望我去打击犯罪
I think he was disappointed I went into crime fighting...
而不是步他后尘
...instead of following him.
我猜我就是对鸟类 航天飞机和神话更感兴趣
Guess I was just more interested in birds and airplanes, mythology and...
再加上已经有不少人在做这个
Plus, there were enough other guys doing
所以我在后面就没感觉太荒谬
so that I didn't feel ridiculous behind.
比如霍利斯
Like Hollis.
对
Yeah.
对 他是我的英雄
Yeah, he was my hero.
哇 我记得第一次遇见他的时候 我…
Man, I remember the first time that I met him...
我就感觉有联系 你知道吗?
...I just felt so connected, you know?
在一些重要的方面
To something that mattered.
有个秘密身份肯定很不错吧?
Must be nice having a secret identity.
有个没人知道的秘密据点
A secret place that nobody knows about.
你可以…进进出出 没人会对你进行安检
You can just come down here and hang out without anyone checking up on you.
没有人监视你
Nobody watching you.
想戴上试试吗?
Wanna try those on?
来吧
There we go.
哇 这太酷了
Wow, these rock.
它放大了光谱范围
They amplify the spectral range.
热成像
Thermal imaging.
黑暗中效果更好
They work even better in the dark.
你能看见我 对吧?
You can see me, right?
我什么都能看见
I can see everything.
我记得 不管外面有多黑
I remember, no matter how black it got...
只要我戴上这副眼镜 一切就像白天一样清楚
...whenever I looked through those goggles, everything was as clear as day.
这一定就是乔恩眼中的世界
This must be the way Jon sees the world.
我们也许该上去了 饭菜快凉了
We should probably head up. Food's getting cold.
看完了把它放回去
Put those away when you're done.
苏联驻联合国大使今天没有任何评论…
MAN [ON TV]: Soviet ambassador to the U.N. had no comment today...
当他被问及曼哈顿博士的消失是否...
... when asked if Dr. Manhattan's disappearance
...加速了苏联在阿富汗的侵略
has fueled Soviet aggression in Afghanistan.
丹
Dan.
乔恩看得见很多东西
Jon sees a lot of things...
但他看不见我
...but he doesn't see me.
这个 嗯...
Well, uh...
哦
Oh.
抱歉
Sorry.
过来
Come here.
怎么了?
What's the matter?
- 你能稍微挪一下… - 好的
- If you could just move a little... - Okay.
嗯 好了
Yeah. There you go.
丹 怎么了?
Dan, what's wrong?
抱歉 我
Sorry, I...
哦 我只是需要几分钟
Yeah, I just need a couple minutes.
哦 见鬼了
Oh, hell.
没事的
It's okay.
可能我们发展太快了
Maybe we were just moving too fast.
我们有大把的时间
We've got all the time in the world.
我们慢慢来
We'll take it slow.
好久不见 罗夏
It's been a long time, Rorschach.
大块头
RORSCHACH: Big Figure.
世界真小
Small world.
我喜欢这样
I like that.
不过你得知道 这地方很小的
But you know, it is a small world in here.
我已经在这里有多久了 洛伊德?
And I've been in it for, how long now, Lloyd?
快15年了 大块头先生
LLO YD: Almost 15 years, Mr. Figure.
说得对
That's right.
自从你和夜枭把我抓进来已经15年了
Fifteen years since you and that Owl fella put me away.
那么
So...
罗夏 你烫伤的那个人快死了 随时可能咽气
...Rorschach, that guy you burned is dying. Could go any minute.
知道吗 我数过 这里有超过50人是你抓进来的
You know, by my count, there are more than 50 people in here that you put away.
我和他们每个人都谈过了
I been talking to every one of them
他们都恨不得要分你的一片肉
and they're all dying to get a piece of you.
这里快要暴乱了
This place is gonna explode!
然后 让你一寸一寸地死
Then, you die by inches.
有点难度
Tall order.
我要给这家伙开个新口子
I'm gonna tear this guy a new hole.
放轻松 劳伦斯 快了
Relax, Lawrence. Soon.
走吧
Come on.
[片段5开始][目标][1:56:12.12][时长][00:04:36.98]
[片段5结束][目标][1:56:12.12][时长][00:04:36.98]
丹?
Dan?
一切都好吧?
Is everything all right?
我厌倦了担惊受怕
I'm tired of being afraid.
害怕战争
Afraid of war...
害怕蒙面杀手
...afraid of the mask killer...
害怕这该死的制服
...and afraid of this goddamn suit...
以及我是多么需要它
...and how much I need it.
我也是
Me too.
那就让他们见鬼去吧
So to hell with it.
我们开阿齐出去吧
Let's take Archie out.
你说真的吗?
You're serious.
我也曾是蒙面复仇者 还记得吧?
I used to be a masked avenger too, remember?
我以前经常半夜3点出去 做一些傻事
I'm used to going out at 3 in the morning and doing something stupid.
紧急火情 所有单位 听候指示
MAN [OVER RADIO]: Rapid burner. Be advised, all units.
第五大街和格兰特大街租屋失火
Tenement fire at 5th and Grand. Rapid burner.
我们走
Let's go.
- 我看到了 - 好的 抓紧了
LAURIE: I can see it. DAN: All right, hold on.
丹 里面有孩子
LAURIE: Dan, there are kids in there.
每个人都请待在原处 保持镇静
Everyone, please stay where you are and remain calm.
我们会把你们救出去的
We're gonna get you out of there.
屋顶就快塌了 让我进去
The roof's starting to cave. Get me in there.
我带你靠近
DAN: I'm gonna get you close.
快走
Let's go.
赶快
Come on.
来 都上去
All right, let's move it, people.
妈妈 那人住在太空火箭里吗?
Mom, is that guy in the space rocket?
那是耶稣吗?
Is that Jesus?
不 宝贝
No, baby.
- 小心脚下  - 好的
DAN: Watch your step. LAURIE: All right.
我们上来了
We're all set.
都到齐了吗?
Is that everyone?
再见！
MAN: Bye. GIRL: Bye!
不敢相信我们这么做了
LAURIE: I can't believe we did that.
- 他们会把我们和罗夏关在一起  - 管他呢
- They'll lock us up with Rorschach. - Who cares?
第三次世界大战可能明天就开打
World War III could start tomorrow.
对吧?
Right?
对
Right.
给我回来！
MAN: Come back here!
他死了 罗夏
He's dead, Rorschach.
趁大家都在忙
While everyone's distracted,
我们想着给送你一份乔迁礼物
we thought we'd bring you a housewarming gift.
机械店买的
Something from the machine shop.
老大 你注意到没有?
Hey, boss, you notice?
没听到"世界真小", "难办"那些废话了
None of that "small world, tall order" crap.
他知道等我们切开他的锁
He knows once we slice open his lock,
下一个切的就是他
he's next on the block.
机会太小
Fat chance.
你死定了 罗夏
You're dead, Rorschach!
我们有一整个监狱的杀手 你有什么?
We got a prison full of killers out here. What do you got?
有你的手 我很乐意
Your hands, my pleasure.
我够不到门锁 要把栏杆锯断吗?
LLO YD: Can't reach the lock. Should I cut the bars?
暴乱不会持续多久 这一刻我等了15年了
This riot won't last. I been waiting 15 years for this.
抱歉劳伦斯 你挡到我复仇了
I'm sorry, Lawrence, but you're in the way of my revenge.
不是针对你的 大块头
Nothing personal, big guy.
老大！等等！
Boss! Wait!
现在你看清楚比分了吧?
Now you find out what the score is.
1比0 进来抓我吧
One-nothing. Come and get me.
快点
Come on.
所以我一直在想
DAN: So I've been thinking.
我觉得我们对这个团体有责任
I feel that we have an obligation to our fraternity.
我想我们应该去救罗夏
I think we ought to spring Rorschach.
什么?
LAURIE: What?
有人陷害了他
DAN: Someone set him up.
还有乔恩跟癌症的事情 完全没有道理
And this whole cancer thing with Jon, it just doesn't make sense.
你就没有得癌
You didn't get it.
对 不过闯入最高安全级别的监狱
Yeah, but breaking into a maximum-security prison...
跟灭火有点不一样
...is a little different than putting out a fire.
没错 你说的对
Yeah, you're right.
会更好玩
It'll be more fun.
快点洛伊德 我想闻到这婊子养的被烤熟
Hurry, Lloyd. I wanna smell this son of a bitch cooking.
好啊
Yes.
不
No.
从来没用马桶处理过污水
Never disposed of sewage with a toilet before.
明显早该用
Obvious, really.
2比0 该你动了
Two-nothing. Your move.
给我让开！
BIG FIGURE: Get out of the way!
你怎么知道他还活着?
How do we know he's still alive?
他还活着
DAN: He's alive.
不要 不
No. No.
我的脸呢?
Where's my face?
别杀我
Don't kill me.
到你了 医生
Your turn, doctor.
告诉我 你看见什么?
Tell me, what do you see?
不许动
Don't move!
罗夏
Rorschach.
丹尼尔 朱庇特小姐
Daniel. Miss Jupiter.
抱歉 得去一下男厕
Excuse me. Have to visit men's room.
哦 老天在上
Oh, for chrissake.
很高兴看见你穿上制服 丹尼尔
RORSCHACH: Good to see you in uniform, Daniel.
早该知道你只需要一双美腿的激励
Should've known all you needed was nice pair of legs to motivate you.
你真是个混蛋 罗夏
LAURIE: You're such an asshole, Rorschach.
原谅我的激愤
Spare me indignation.
你挑了个好时间对乔恩不忠
Picked hell of a time to be unfaithful to Jon.
是厌倦了爱国精神 还是有人逼你那么做?
Get tired of being patriotic, or someone put you up to it?
知道吗 你他妈的不知道自己在说什么！
You don't know what the fuck you're talking about!
嘿 你俩能停下吗 你们可以回头再吵
Hey! Would you two stop? You can argue later.
我不得不把警报器关了 所以我们很快会招来火力
I had to turn the screechers off, so we'll be drawing fire soon.
站住！站住！不然开枪了！
Stop! Stop or we will shoot!
你还好吗?
Are you all right?
还好 只是…
Yeah. Just...
觉得沉重 你知道的
...heavy, you know?
战争 越狱
War, jailbreak.
别担心 好吗?
Don't worry about it. Okay?
一切都会好的
Everything's gonna be fine.
- 你好 劳瑞  - 乔恩
- Hello, Laurie. - Jon.
电视上说你在火星
TV said you were on Mars.
我是在火星
I am on Mars.
你跟我要在那里谈谈
You and I are about to have a conversation there.
你在说什么?
What are you talking about?
你要努力说服我去拯救这个世界
You're going to try to convince me to save the world.
劳瑞 不要
Laurie, don't.
丹 相信我
Dan, trust me.
我必须去
I have to go.
很美 不是吗?
Beautiful, isn't it?
原谅我 我有时会漏掉这些事情
Forgive me. These things sometimes slip my mind.
不会再发生了
It won't happen again.
令人欣慰
LAURIE: That's comforting.
哦 我的天啊
Oh, my God.
我在火星上
I'm on Mars.
- 嘿 屁股不错 - 嘿 混蛋
MAN: Hey. Nice ass. WOMAN: Hey, asshole.
嘿 我们看看那个爱看漫画的在不在这里
MAN: Hey, let's see if that comic-book retard's up here.
嘿嘿嘿 喂
Hey, hey, hey. Yo.
你们都听说了吗?
You all hear?
有个超级猫头鹰哥们劫狱带走了罗夏
Some super-owl dude just busted Rorschach out of prison.
- 罗夏?  - 对
- Rorschach? - Yeah.
那个混蛋把我表哥打到坐轮椅
That fool put my cousin in a wheelchair.
你是说夜枭 他之前和罗夏是搭档 记得吗?
You mean Nite Owl. Him and Rorschach used to be partners, remember?
- 对 - 可能他也惹过你表哥
- Yeah. - Maybe he messed your cousin up too.
- 他是不是写过一本书什么的?  - 对
- Didn't he write a book or something? - Yeah.
告诉你 他住在一个加油站边 就在这附近
You know, he lives over a garage right near here.
- 是吗?  - 是这样吗?
- Yeah? - Does he, now?
喂?
SALLY [ON PHONE]: Hello?
莎莉?
HOLLIS: Sally?
- 霍利斯?  - 是我
- Hollis? - Yeah.
哇 霍利斯·梅森 老天
Yes, Hollis Mason. Jesus.
你一直都有我的号码 却等到我们日薄西山才打?
All this time you've had my number and you wait until our sunset years to use it?
哦 看来这是个特殊的场合 小莎
HOLLIS: Well, it seemed like a special occasion, Sal.
怎么了?
What?
电视正在报道昨晚有场公寓火灾
The TV is reporting there was a tenement fire last night.
受困人群是被一艘飞船救出的
There were trapped people rescued by airship...
他们说驾驶者穿得像猫头鹰一样
... and they say the pilot was dressed like an owl.
好像还有个性感女人和他一起
And it seems he had a sexy woman with him.
劳瑞? 我的女儿 劳瑞?
Laurie? My daughter, Laurie?
我说服不了劳瑞再穿上制服
I can't get over Laurie back in costume.
或许她最后会感谢我 一开始把她带上这条路
Maybe she'll finally thank me for getting her started in the first place.
小莎 听你说话的声音
You know, Sal, by the sound of your voice...
你比以前还年轻
...you're sounding younger than ever.
哦 祝福你 霍利斯
Oh. Why, bless you, Hollis.
不过我还是老了
But that's probably just senility.
能和你聊天很开心 小莎
Well, it's been great talking to you, Sal...
但是有人在敲门
...but someone's knocking.
好的 想起旧日时光不要太泪目了
SALLY: Well, don't get too misty-eyed thinking about old times.
你保重 霍利斯
You take care now, Hollis.
你也是
Ah, you too.
拜
Bye.
我们想找猫头鹰先生
MAN 1: We're looking for Mr. Owl.
在 别着急
Yeah. Hold your horses.
猫头鹰先生 你在吗?
MAN 1: Mr. Owl, you there?
不给糖就捣乱
MAN 2: Trick or treat.
你应该好好退你的休 猫头鹰
MAN 1: You should've stayed retired, Owl.
我讨厌这样
RORSCHACH: I hate this.
畏缩在洞里 躲避着当局
Cowering in cave, hiding from authorities.
警察在外面追捕我们
Cops are out there hunting us.
除非你想回监狱
Unless you wanna go back to prison
没有计划地随便暴露自己很愚蠢
we'd be stupid to expose ourselves without a plan.
那要怎么样?
And what would that be?
一旦我们找出其中模式
Once we've established a pattern...
我们就能入侵金字塔公司 看看能发现什么
...we can break into Pyramid, see what we find.
做过了 死胡同
RORSCHACH: Did that. Dead end.
我认为那只是个掩护幕后人用的公司 但不能证明
I think it's a front company for whoever's really behind it, but can't prove it.
我们需要敲打黑社会的线人 逼问那些人
We need to hit up underworld contacts, squeeze people.
是啊 我们干嘛不直接从电话簿里挑人问?
Sure, why don't we just pick names out of a phone book?
你忘了我们以前是怎么做事的 丹尼尔
You forgot how we do things, Daniel.
你变得太软 太轻信 特别是面对女人
You've gone too soft. Too trusting. Especially with women.
好了 住嘴 听着 我受够了
Okay, no. Listen, I've had it with that.
天哪 你以为你是谁 罗夏?
God, who do you think you are, Rorschach?
你污蔑自己投靠的人
You live off people while insulting them...
没人会埋怨你 因为他们都觉得你是个该死的疯子
...and no one complains because they think you're a goddamn lunatic.
抱歉 我…
I'm sorry.
我不该那么说 老兄
I shouldn't have said that, man.
丹尼尔
Daniel...
你是个好朋友
...you are a good friend.
我知道我有时候比较难相处
I know it can be difficult with me sometimes.
算了
Forget it.
没事的 伙计
It's okay, man.
就照你的办法做
Let's do it your way.
哦 老天
Oh, God.
金字塔跨国公司 有人听说过吗?
Pyramid Transnational. Anyone heard of it?
哦 你们这些混蛋
Oh, you bastards.
我请这里每个人喝酒 你们就这样出卖我?
I buy everyone a round and you sell me out like this?
退后 不然我就把这杯子 黏在你潮湿的脸上
Back off, or I'll stick this glass in your squidgy face.
大家保持冷静 我们尽量简短
Everybody stay calm. We'll try to keep this brief.
罗伊·切斯 领金字塔的工资
Roy Chess. On Pyramid payroll.
试图谋杀阿德里安·维特 现在已经死了
Tried to kill Adrian Veidt. Dead now.
你认识他吗?
Did you know him?
不
No.
知道 知道
Yeah, yeah!
我雇了他 我在牢里认识的他
I hired him. I knew him from the inside.
你是重刑犯
You're a felon.
以前是 但出狱后我就改过自新了 我发誓
I was. I've been straight ever since I got out, I swear.
我没那么了解切斯
I barely knew Chess that well,
但我被告知要去雇佣以前认识的人
but I was told to hire from the old life.
谁让你做的?
Told by whom?
我的接头人 斯莱特小姐
My contact, Miss Slater.
珍妮·斯莱特? 也为金字塔工作?
Janey Slater works for Pyramid too?
对 她是个好人
Yeah, she was real nice.
她说公司政策支持雇佣有前科的人
She said hiring ex-cons was part of the company program.
给人第二次机会
Give people a second chance.
老天 松手吧 我说的是实话
God, please let go! I'm telling the truth!
珍妮·斯莱特 曼哈顿的前女友
Janey Slater, Manhattan's old girlfriend.
阿德里安的人也许能帮我们查到谁在金字塔背后
Adrian's peaple might help us find out who's underwriting Pyramid.
跟着钱查
Follow the money.
前民兵成员霍利斯·梅森被发现遭到杀害…
WOMAN [ON TV]:former member of the Minutemen Hollis Mason found murdered...
不到一个小时之前在其公寓内
... in his apartment less than an hour ago.
目击者报告称 看见本地结首帮的几名成员…
Witnesses reported seeing members of a local gang known as the Knot-Tops...
大约在估计的死亡时间离开了现场
... leaving the area right around the estimated time of death.
现场直播 蒂芙尼·伯恩斯…
Reporting live, Tiffany Burns...
是谁干的?
Who did it?
我就知道你想怪在我身上 老兄
I knew you were gonna victimize me, man.
我的公民权利呢? 就因为我穿了一件…
What about my civil rights? Just because I'm wearing...
- 告诉我谁干的?  - 很多人都这么穿
- Tell me who did it! - A lot of people dress like this.
谁杀了霍利斯·梅森?
Who murdered Hollis Mason?
告诉你的朋友们 他们死定了
You tell your friends they're dead.
我要踏平你们整个老巢！
I'm gonna take out this entire rathole neighborhood.
我要拧断你的脖子！
I'll break your neck!
丹尼尔 别在公众面前这样
Daniel, not in front of the civilians.
该死的 该死的 霍利斯
Oh, goddamn. Goddamn, Hollis.
这就是我们要谈话的地方
JON: This is where we hold our conversation.
在这里 你向我揭示你和德雷伯格一起睡了
In it, you reveal to me that you and Dreiberg have been sleeping together.
你知道我和丹的事情?
You know about me and Dan?
现在还不知道
Not yet.
但是过一会儿你就会告诉我
But in a few moments you're going to tell me.
如果你已经知道未来 那么…
If you already know the future, then...
我离开你时你干嘛还惊讶?
why were you surprised when I left you?
还有那个记者突袭陷害你的时候?
Or when that reporter ambushed you?
为什么还要争论呢? 你一早就知道结果如何了
Why even argue about it if you already know how this is gonna end?
我没有选择
I have no choice.
每一件事都是预定的
Everything is preordained.
连我的反应也是
Even my responses.
所以你只是走个过场
And you're just going through the motions.
宇宙中最强大的事物 仍然只是个傀儡
The most powerful thing in the universe is still just a puppet.
我们都是傀儡 劳瑞
We are all puppets, Laurie.
只不过我能看到控制我的绳子
I'm just a puppet who can see the strings.
万一你错了呢?
And what if you're wrong?
为什么我对时间的知觉 会如此困扰你呢?
Why does my perception of time distress you so?
因为那是非人的
Because it's inhuman.
因为那让我发疯
Because it makes me insane.
你总是说你要安慰我 但是都没有起作用
You always say you wanna comfort me. Well, it isn't working.
听着 我不想争吵
Look, I don't wanna fight.
我抱歉我跟丹睡了
I'm sorry I slept with Dan.
你和丹睡了?
You slept with Dan?
你刚才说过 你已经知道了
You just said that you already knew about that.
我经常说
I said often...
你是我唯一剩下的跟人类的联系
...that you were my only remaining link to humanity.
为什么我要去拯救一个与我无关的世界呢?
Why would I save a world I no longer have any stake in?
那就为了我而做
Then do it for me.
如果你真的在乎
If you really care.
当你离开了我 我离开了地球
When you left me, I left Earth.
那还不够表示我的真心吗?
Does that not show you that I care?
我的红色世界 此时此地
My red world here, now...
对我而言比你们的蓝色世界更有意义
...means more to me than your blue one.
我给你看看
Let me show you.
炸弹都已加注燃料并准备好 先生
KISSINGER: Bombers are fueled and ready, sir.
是时候了 各位
It's time, gentlemen.
把我们的戒备状态升到1级
Take us to DEFCON one.
不在顶楼公寓 不在办公室
RORSCHACH: Not in penthouse. Not in office.
什么样的夜行癖好 诱使一个拥有一切的男人
What nocturnal proclivities entice a man with everything...
在晚上这时候外出?
...out into the night at this hour?
丹尼尔?
Daniel?
你还在线吗
You with me?
是的
Yeah.
那你在干什么?
Then what are you doing?
我去找阿德里安的日程表
DAN: I'm gonna look for Adrian's itinerary.
也许他有存档
RORSCHACH: Maybe he keeps on file.
- 有些事不对头  - 同意
- Something's not right. - Agreed.
珍妮·斯莱特 摩罗神 罗伊·切斯 都为金字塔工作
Janey Slater, Moloch, Roy Chess all work for Pyramid.
摩罗神说笑匠提到一个名单
Moloch said the Comedian mentioned list
有他和斯莱特的名字在上面
with his and Slater's name on it.
掌管金字塔公司的人很可能
Whoever owns Pyramid
就是让这些人患上癌症的人
could be giving these people cancer.
陷害曼哈顿
Setting Manhattan up.
(法老王)
(拒绝访问)
有趣
Funny.
古代的法老盼着世界末日到来
Ancient pharaohs looked forward to the end of the world.
他们相信尸体会复起 从金罐子里取回自己的心脏
Believed cadavers would rise, reclaim hearts from golden jars.
现在他们一定正屏息以待
Must currently be holding breath in anticipation.
法老?
Pharaohs?
找到一份曼哈顿的心理档案
Got a psych profile on Manhattan.
看看那些企业的大脑窥探者怎么说
See what the corporate head-peepers say.
"对象持续情感退化"
"Subject continues to retreat emotionally.
"如果仅剩的情感连接被切断"
If the only remaining ties were to be severed...
拉美西斯二世(法老)
"我们预测会完全脱离人类本性"
...we predict total detachment from the human condition."
我进入了
DAN: I'm in.
(母公司：维特国际)
不
No.
恭喜 维特先生
MAN: Congratulations, Mr. Veidt.
曼哈顿博士的能量反应堆已经连上了
Dr. Manhattan's energy reactor is online.
你的支持 还有你的热忱
Your support and your enthusiasm...
促成了这次胜利
...is what has led to this triumph.
我们代表研究团队 向你致敬
On behalf of the research team, we salute you.
- 干杯 - 干杯
- Cheers. - Cheers.
生命中有什么不值得庆祝?
ADRIAN: What in life does not deserve celebrating?
这就是新的卡纳克神庙
This is the new Karnak.
这代表了一个两千年之久的梦想的顶点
This represents the culmination of a dream more than 2000 years old...
一个因为你们坚定不移的支持而实现的梦想
...a dream now assured because of your unquestioning assistance.
为此
And for this...
我有愧于你们
...I am ashamed...
愧在你们必须共享这样微薄的奖励
...ashamed that you must now share such inadequate a reward.
敬法老们
To the pharaohs...
他们把最伟大的秘密托付给仆人
...their greatest secrets entrusted to their servants...
活埋在了黄沙覆盖的厅堂里
...buried alive with them in sand-floored chambers.
好梦 先生们
Sleep well, gentlemen.
我们的新的和平世界将受惠于…
Our new, peaceful world will be indebted...
你们伟大的牺牲
...to your great sacrifice.
布巴斯提斯 古埃及的猫神
Bubastis.
罗夏日记 最后的记录
Rorschach's journal. Final entry.
维特是一切的幕后主使
Veidt's behind everything.
为什么?
Why?
他的最终目的是什么?
What's his endgame?
我想不出比他更危险的对手
I cannot imagine a more dangerous opponent.
曾经开玩笑说他快到能抓住子弹
Used to joke he was fast enough to catch a bullet.
他一个人在雪地里能够干掉我们俩
He could kill us both alone in the snow.
那就是我们要去的地方：南极
That's where we're going now: Antarctica.
无论这文字被读到时我是生是死
Whether I'm alive or dead upon this reading...
我希望这个世界存活时间够长 让你们能得到这本日记
... I hope the world survives long enough for this journal to reach you.
我的一生没有妥协
I live my life free of compromise...
步入死亡阴影也没有抱怨和后悔
... and step into the shadow without complaint or regret.
罗夏 11月1号
Rorschach, November 1 st.
你就不能直接告诉我结局吗? 省得经历那些麻烦
LAURIE: Can't you just tell me how this ends and save us the trouble?
[片段6开始][目标][2:27:10.91][时长][00:04:51.79]
[片段6结束][目标][2:27:10.91][延迟][00:04:51.79]
它会以你的眼泪结束
JON: It ends with you in tears.
眼泪?
Tears?
那么你不回地球了?
So you don't come back to Earth.
在某个时刻 是的
At some point, yes.
街道上满是死亡
The streets are filled with death.
乔恩 拜托
Jon, please.
你必须阻止这一切 每个人都会死
You have to stop this. Everyone will die.
而宇宙根本不会察觉
And the universe will not even notice.
在我看来 生命的存在
In my opinion, the existence of life...
是一种被过度高估的现象
...is a highly overrated phenomenon.
看看你的周围吧
Just look around you.
火星上没有一丝微小生物 仍然运行得如此完美
Mars gets along perfectly well without so much as a microorganism.
这儿 是一幅永远在变化的地形图
Here, it's a constantly changing topographical map...
围绕着地极流动变换 跨越千年
...flowing and shifting around the pole in ripples 10,000 years wide.
告诉我
So tell me...
增加一条输油管道哪里会使这一切更美好?
...how would all of this be greatly improved by an oil pipeline?
或者增加一个购物中心?
By a shopping mall?
难道向你请求一个奇迹很过分吗?
So it's too much to ask you for a miracle?
奇迹 按照他们的定义 是无意义的
Miracles, by their definition, are meaningless.
哦 老天 乔恩！
Oh, God, Jon!
只有能够发生的才会发生
- Only what can happen does happen.
别再胡说八道
Just stop your bullshit.
让这东西着陆 马上
Land this thing. Now.
如你所愿
JON: As you wish.
你知道吗?
LAURIE: You know what?
你可以把我送回地球 让我和丹和我妈妈一起被烤焦
You can send me back to Earth to fry with Dan and my mom...
还有其他无用的人类一起
...and all the other worthless humans.
但要知道你错了
But know that you were wrong.
你说过这会以我的眼泪结束
You said this ended with me in tears...
看吧 什么也没有
...and look: Nothing.
也许你全都错了
Maybe you were wrong about everything.
你抱怨我拒绝以生命的视角来看待生命
You complain that I refuse to see life on life's terms...
然而你不断地拒绝从我的视角去看待事情
...yet you continuously refuse to see things from my perspective.
你把害怕的东西拒之门外
You shut out what you're afraid of.
我不害怕
I'm not afraid.
你要我按你的方式看待事物吗?
You want me to see things your way?
来吧 给我看看 照你那样来做
Go ahead, show me. Do that thing you do.
魔法 梦想 那是我以前拥有的
Magic. Dreams. That is what I had before.
我曾经是个英雄 该死的
I was a hero, goddamn it!
你变老了又不是我的错 你有什么好抱怨的?
It's not my fault you got old. What do you have to complain about?
我给你和你的孩子 提供餐桌上的食物
I put food on the table for you and your child.
你干嘛不打电话给你朋友艾迪?
Why don't you call your friend Eddie?
也许他能给你更好的生活
Maybe he can give you a better life.
即使是最肮脏的部分
SALLY: Even the grimy parts of it...
也越来越明亮
...keep on getting brighter.
知道吗? 你妈妈她以前是历史选美冠军
You know, your mom, she was one of the all-time champion beauties.
- 你有她的眼睛 你还有…  - 把你手拿开
- You got her eyes, you know. You got... - Take your hands off her.
嘿 美人 好久不见
EDDIE: Hey, doll. Long time no see.
对我来说还不够久 埃迪
Not long enough in my book, Eddie.
上车
Get in the car.
立刻
Now.
你的沉沦完全没有底线吗?
Are there no depths you won't sink to?
老天 莎莉 一个人就不能跟他的…
Jesus Christ, Sally. Can't a guy talk to his...
…老朋友的女儿说说话吗?
...you know, old friend's daughter?
开车
Drive.
那是个错误 就那一次
SALLY: It was a mistake. One time.
那个试图强奸你的人 几年后你倒让他得手了?
Guy tries to rape you, and years later, you let him finish the job?
怎么? 当时你喝醉了还是寂寞了?
What? Were you drunk or just lonely?
难道我这辈子都不能放下这件事?
Am I ever gonna live this down?
劳瑞
Laurie.
不
No.
不 不是他
No, not him.
笑匠
The Comedian...
是你的父亲
...was your father.
不
No.
不！不！不！
No! No! No!
我的人生就是…
My life is just...
一个大笑话
...one big joke.
我并不觉得你的人生是个笑话
I don't think your life is a joke.
好吧
Yeah, well...
抱歉 我不相信你的幽默感
...I'm sorry if I don't trust your sense of humor.
如果我承认我错了
Will you smile...
你会笑一笑吗?
...if I admit I was wrong?
关于什么事?
LAURIE: About what?
奇迹
Miracles.
天文级数级别的小概率事件发生 比如…
Events with astronomical odds of occurring like...
…氧气变成金子
...oxygen turning into gold.
我一直渴望见证这样的事件 然而我却忽视了…
I've longed to witness such an event, and yet I neglect that...
…人类的结合
...in human coupling...
数以百万的细胞争相创造一个生命
...millions upon millions of cells compete to create life...
一代又一代 直到…
...for generation after generation until...
终于 你的母亲
... finally, your mother...
爱上了一个男人
...loves a man...
艾德华·布雷克 笑匠
...Edward Blake, the Comedian,
一个她有百般理由去憎恨的人
a man she has every reason to hate...
在种种矛盾之中 违反这微乎其微的概率
...and out of that contradiction, against unfathomable odds...
是你…
...it's you...
唯一的
Only...
你
...you.
显现出来
That emerged.
要在所有的混沌中…
To distill so specific a form...
提取出这样特定的一个形体
...from all that chaos...
就像是把空气变成了金子
...is like turning air into gold.
一个奇迹
A miracle.
因此
And so...
我错了
...I was wrong.
擦干眼泪 我们回家吧
Now dry your eyes, and let's go home.
我们已经发现了那个人造设施的方位
We got a bearing on that artificial structure.
热力信号破表了
Heat signature's off the charts.
维特
Veidt.
我觉得阿奇的状态不对劲
I don't like the way Archie's kicking.
(警告：引擎故障)
- 是引擎  - 它们在结冰 抓牢了
- The engines. - They're icing up. Hold onto something.
丹尼尔 你飞得太低了
Daniel, you're coming in too low.
不是想干扰 但是也许应该立刻拉升
Don't wish to interfere, but perhaps should pull up sharply...
我知道 我正在尝试 该死的
I know! I'm trying. I'm trying to pull him up, goddamn it!
我打算重定向喷射的热量 加快除冰
DAN: I'm gonna redirect the heat from the flamethrower to speed up deicing...
不过这需要一阵子 我们没有时间等
...but it's gonna take a while and we don't have time to wait.
你需要穿点更暖和的
You need something warmer.
我穿这就行
Fine like this.
怎么了 姑娘?
What is it, girl?
阿德里安是和平主义者
DAN: Adrian's a pacifist.
他是个素食者 老天在上
He's a vegetarian, for chrissakes.
他一生没杀过一个人
He's never killed anyone in his life.
希特勒也是素食主义者
Hitler was vegetarian.
你心态崩了 把他交给我吧
You're squeamish, leave him to me.
我们没有第二次机会
We won't get second chance.
先生们
Gentlemen.
欢迎
Welcome.
阿德里安 我们全都知道了
Adrian, we know everything.
那我们还有什么好说的 丹?
Then what's there to discuss, Dan?
多着呢 你杀了笑匠
Plenty. You killed Comedian.
愿他安息
May he rest in peace.
布雷克是第一个发现真相的
Blake figured it out first.
尼克松派他监视我们 确保我们不会坏事
Nixon had him keeping tabs on us, making sure we weren't rocking the boat.
布雷克发现了我在卡纳克这里做的事情
Blake found out what I was doing here in Karnak...
他去拜访可怜的摩罗神的时候 已经崩溃得不行了
... and by the time he visited poor Moloch, he was cracking badly.
连我都没料到他会是个改邪归正的人
Even I couldn't predict he'd be the one to have a change of heart.
所以
So...
我不得不杀了他
...I had to kill him.
然后我摆平了乔恩 这任务不容易
Then I neutralized Jon. No easy task.
我花了约20亿研究超光速粒子
I put roughly $2 billion into tachyon research...
用来屏蔽乔恩的未来感知
...to block Jon's vision of the future.
你利用他的心理档案操纵了他
RORSCHACH: You used his psych profile to manipulate him.
让他离开了这个星球
Got him to leave the planet.
我认识乔恩很久了 知道他并非脱离情感
I've known Jon long enough to see he isn't devoid of emotion.
他微妙的面部表情抽动 外人不易察觉
His subtle facial twitches wouldn't be noticed by the layman,
但对我而言 就像啜泣一样明显
but to me, he might as well have been sobbing.
我要做的 就是顺势牵动那根线
All I needed to do was tug on the thread.
当他相信他给所爱的人带去癌症
The sudden flood of emotion Jon felt...
那种突然的情感冲击…
... when he came to believe he'd given cancer to the people he loved...
足以构成他离开地球的理由
... was all the excuse he needed to leave Earth.
你那个狗屁刺客 你花钱雇他来误导我们
DAN: Your bullshit assassin. You paid him to throw us off.
切斯先生为更崇高的使命献出生命 丹
ADRIAN: Mr. Chess gave his life in the service of a higher cause, Dan.
我放了一个氰化物胶囊在他嘴里
I put a cyanide capsule in his mouth...
这下只剩下一个未解决的隐患
... leaving only one loose end:
就是你 还有你的蒙面杀手理论
You, and your mask-killer theory...
靠着你的反社会人格穷追不舍
... one you followed with the tenacity of a true sociopath.
我给警察提前通风报信
I tipped off the police.
一旦你进了监狱 我就能继续行动
Once you were in prison, I was able to move forward.
抱歉让你失望了
RORSCHACH: Sorry to disappoint you.
我们本该让世界更美好
DAN: We were supposed to make the world a better place.
丹 那正是我在做的事
ADRIAN: Dan, that's exactly what I am doing.
核战?
DAN: Nuclear war?
灭绝人类?
Human extinction?
当然 我的道德保障让我适可而止 避免过多的牺牲
ADRIAN: Of course, my moral safeguards gave me pause at the necessary sacrifice.
只毁灭全球少数几个关键地区
A few key regions around the globe...
纽约 洛杉矶 莫斯科 香港
New York, Los Angeles, Moscow, Hong Kong.
瞬间瓦解
Disintegrated in an instant.
1500万人被曼哈顿博士杀死
Fifteen million people killed by Dr. Manhattan himself.
作为挑动第三次世界大战的惩罚
The world's punishment for flirting with World War III.
乔恩不会做这种事的
Jon wouldn't do that.
这个房间之外的人们又不知道这点
A fact no one outside this room ever has to know.
我一直致力的能源突破刚刚取得成果
The energy breakthrough I was working on just came to fruition.
这些年来 乔恩一直在帮我复制他的能量
All these years, Jon was helping me replicate his power...
却不知道我打算怎么用它
...unaware of how I planned to use it.
你们看…
You see...
笑匠是对的
...the Comedian was right.
人性的野蛮本性将必然导致全球毁灭
Humanity's savage nature will inevitably lead to global annihilation.
所以为了拯救这个星球
So in order to save this planet...
我必须欺骗它…
...I had to trick it...
用人类历史上最伟大的恶作剧
...with the greatest practical joke in human history.
- 杀死上百万人  - 拯救数亿人
- Killing millions. - To save billions.
必要的犯罪
A necessary crime.
你知道我们不可能让你去做的
RORSCHACH: You know we can't let you do that.
"去做" 罗夏?
"Do that," Rorschach?
我不是漫画书式的反派
I'm not a comic-book villain.
但凡你们有一丝可能性能影响我的计划
Do you seriously think I'd explain my masterstroke to you...
我会站在这里给你们解释我的高招吗?
...if there were even the slightest possibility you could affect the outcome?
我在35分钟前就启动了
I triggered it 35 minutes ago.
(东京 伦敦 巴黎 北京 莫斯科 纽约)
[片段7][目标][2:41:50.55][时长][00:02:29.81]
(纽约邮报：战争? )
老天爷 亨利
Jesus Christ, Henry.
为什么我们没侦测到发射?
Why the hell didn't we get a launch detection?
不是苏联发射的 先生
It's not the Soviets, sir.
情报显示这个能量特征的引发者是…
Intel indicates the energy signature was generated by...
曼哈顿博士
...Dr. Manhattan.
乔恩
Jon.
干扰
Interference.
灾难性的干扰
Cataclysmic interference.
我不敢相信这件事发生了
LAURIE: I can't believe it happened.
这不是由核弹头引起的
This wasn't caused by nuclear warheads.
是我
It was me.
我…
I...
造成的
...did this.
你什么意思? 是你造成的?
What do you mean, you did this?
不是直接的
Not directly.
它做成像是我造成的
It was made to look like I did it.
阿德里安
Adrian.
说到就到
Speak of the devil.
- 乔恩  - 我知道
DAN: Jon... JON: I know.
必须阻止他 他杀了布雷克 杀了上百万人
RORSCHACH: Must stop him. Killed Blake, killed millions.
在这等着
Wait here.
阿德里安 收手吧
Adrian, stop this.
超光速粒子那招很聪明
The tachyons were clever...
但即便我无法预测你在哪 我也能把这些墙变成玻璃
...but even if I can't predict where you are, I can turn the walls to glass.
我该谢谢你
I should thank you.
我几乎忘了"不知道"的兴奋感
I'd almost forgotten the excitement of not knowing...
不确定带来的快乐
... the delights of uncertainty.
原谅我 姑娘
Forgive me, girl.
你就是个混蛋
You're such an asshole.
维特 你这杂种
DAN: Veidt, you bastard.
- 你要敢伤害她 我就…  - 丹
- If you've hurt her, I'Il... - Dan...
长大点吧 我的新世界需要少一点英雄主义
...grow up. My new world demands less obvious heroism.
你的…
Your...
小男生似的英雄行为是多余的
...schoolboy heroics are redundant.
它成就过什么吗?
What have they achieved?
没能阻止我拯救地球
Failing to prevent Earth's salvation...
就是你们唯一的功绩
...is your only triumph.
我对你失望了 阿德里安
JON: I'm disappointed in you, Adrian.
我非常失望
I'm very disappointed.
重组我自己是我学到的第一招
Reassembling myself was the first trick I learned.
它没能杀死奥斯特曼 曼哈顿博士的本名
It didn't kill Osterman.
你真的以为它能杀死我吗?
Did you really think it would kill me?
我在太阳表面行走过
I have walked across the surface of the sun.
我见证过一些及其微小而又迅速的事情
I have witnessed events so tiny and so fast...
甚至很难说它们发生过
...they can hardly be said to have occurred at all...
而你 阿德里安 只是个凡人而已
...but you, Adrian, you're just a man.
世界上最聪明的人 对我构成的威胁
The world's smartest man poses no more threat to me...
不会比最聪明的白蚁大多少
...than does its smartest termite.
这是什么?
What's that?
又一个终极武器?
Another ultimate weapon?
是的
Yes.
可以这么说
You could say that.
遭受攻击
- came under attack.
数以万计的人死于非命
Millions of lives were suddenly ended...
这是曼哈顿博士本人的邪恶罪行
... in an act of evil perpetrated by Dr. Manhattan himself.
自从攻击开始 我就持续与苏联的首脑保持联系
Since the attacks, I have been in constant contact with the premier of the U.S.S.R.
放下我们过去的分歧
Putting aside our past differences...
我们双方都承诺联合起来…
... we have both pledged to unite...
对付这个共同的敌人
... against this common enemy.
同全世界一起
With the rest of the world...
我们将会胜利
... we will prevail.
我们永远不会忘记的一天
This is a day we shall never forget.
而我们会前行保卫人类
And yet we go forward to defend the human race...
以及我们这世界的所有美好和正义
... and all that is good and just in our world.
谢谢 愿上帝保佑我们
Thank you. God bless us all.
看见没?
ADRIAN: Do you see?
两个超级大国 放弃了战争
Two superpowers retreating from war.
我把地球从地狱中救了出来
I've saved the earth from hell.
我们俩一起
We both have.
这其中有一半是你的功劳
This is as much your victory as it is mine.
(紧急会议在华盛顿特区召开)
(曼哈顿博士攻击纽约)
现在我们能回去…
Now we can return...
干我们该干的事了
...do what we were meant to.
我们要做的是执行正义
We were meant to exact justice.
所有人都会知道你做了什么
Everyone's gonna know what you've done.
是吗?
Will they?
揭发我 你就会葬送今天这么多死者换来的和平
By exposing me, you would sacrifice the peace so many died for today.
基于谎言的和平
Peace based on a lie.
也是和平
But peace...
…无论如何
...nonetheless.
他说得对
He's right.
揭发阿德里安只会让世界重新陷入核毁灭的厄运
Exposing Adrian would only doom the world to nuclear destruction again.
不
No.
我们不能这样做
We can't do this.
在火星上
On Mars...
你教会了我生命的价值
...you taught me the value of life.
如果想维系这里的生命
If we hope to preserve it here...
我们必须保持沉默
...we must remain silent.
你们自己保守秘密吧
Keep your own secrets.
想都不要想
Don't even think about it.
罗夏
Rorschach.
等等
Wait.
永不妥协
Never compromise.
即便面临世界末日
Not even in the face of armageddon.
这一直是我们俩之间的分别 丹尼尔
That's always been the difference between us, Daniel.
我让自己去感受每一个死亡
I've made myself feel every death...
去看每一张我为拯救人类而谋杀的无辜的脸
...see every innocent face I've murdered to save humanity.
你能理解 不是吗?
You understand, don't you?
既不纵容…
JON: Without condoning...
也不谴责…
...or condemning...
我理解
...I understand.
让开 人们必须知到真相
Out of my way. People have to be told.
你知道我不能让你这么做
You know I can't let you do that.
突然间你又发现人性了?
Suddenly you discover humanity?
真是方便
Convenient.
如果你一开始就关心的话
If you'd cared from the start
这些事情都不会发生
none of this would have happened.
我能几乎能改变任何事物
I can change almost anything...
但改变不了人的本性
...but I can't change human nature.
当然 你必须保护维特的新乌托邦
Of course you must protect Veidt's new utopia.
地基里多一具尸体又如何?
What's one more body amongst foundations?
那你还等什么?
Well, what are you waiting for?
动手吧！
Do it.
动手啊！
Do it!
不！
No!
我要离开这个星系 去一个没这么复杂的地方
JON: I'm leaving this galaxy for one a little less complicated.
我以为你又开始在意生命了呢
LAURIE: I thought you said you cared about life again.
我在意
JON: I do.
也许我还会去创造一些
I think maybe I'll create some.
再见 劳瑞
Goodbye, Laurie.
来啊
Come on.
Come on!
丹
Dan...
一个团结又和平的世界
...a world united and at peace.
必然会有牺牲
There had to be sacrifice.
不！
No!
你没有理想化人类 你扭曲了人性
You haven't idealized mankind, you've deformed it.
你肢解了它
You've mutilated it.
那才是你的遗产
That's your legacy.
那才是真正的恶作剧
That's the real practical joke.
重复一遍 您的电视机没有任何问题
MAN [ON TV]: We repeat, there is nothing wrong with your television set.
您即将参与一次伟大的冒险
You are about to participate in a great adventure.
您即将体验恐惧和神秘
You are about to experience the awe and mystery...
从心灵的最深处一直到最远的边界
... which reaches from the inner mind to the outer limits.
你确定不来一杯吗?
SALLY: Sure you don't want a drink?
我没事
I'm okay.
干杯
Cheers.
有些事情我需要说出来
There's something I need to get off my chest.
我知道艾迪·布雷克是我的父亲
I know that Eddie Blake was my father.
劳瑞
Laurel.
你会怎么看我
What you must think of me.
对不起我从没告诉你
I'm sorry I never told you.
我本来应该说的
I should have...
我不知道 我觉得丢人 我觉得很傻
...but I don't know, I just felt ashamed. I felt stupid.
没关系的
It doesn't matter.
生命会带人去奇怪的地方 做奇怪的事情
People's lives take them strange places. They do strange things...
而且 有时候就是无法言说
...and, well, sometimes they can't talk about them.
我知道那是什么感觉
I know how that is...
但我只想让你知道
...but I just want you to know that...
你对我 从来没有做错什么
...you never did anything wrong by me.
你问过我 为什么不生他的气
You asked me why I wasn't mad at him.
因为他把你给了我
Because he gave me you.
谢谢你 妈妈
Thanks, Mom.
我爱你
I love you.
你好 朱庇特小姐
Hello, Miss Jupiter.
哦 请叫莎莉
Oh, Sally, please.
抱歉 我得去梳洗了
Excuse me. Gotta go freshen up.
一会儿就回来
I'll be right back.
- 你在这边怎么样?   - 不错 你那边呢?
- So how's it going up here? - Good. How's it going down there?
不错 我想我把事情都理顺了
Good. I think I've got everything working.
阿奇的所有系统都升级好了 目前已经捣鼓完毕
All of Archie's systems are upgraded. Finished the tinkering for now...
我们要做的是开它出去兜风
...so all we gotta do is take her out.
哇哦 听着像是个约会
Well, that sounds like a date.
我们会没事吗?
Are we gonna be all right?
只要人们还认为乔恩在盯着我们 就会没事
Long as people think Jon's still watching us, we'll be all right...
…到最后
...in the end.
我知道乔恩会说什么
I know what Jon would say:
世事无尽头
Nothing ends.
世事从无尽头
Nothing ever ends.
西摩尔
Seymour
我们没有什么可写的了
we got nothing to write about anymore.
全国每个人
Everyone in the country...
世界上的每个国家都手拉手
...every country in the world are holding hands...
唱着和平与爱的歌
...and singing songs about peace and love.
就像是住在一个该死的嬉皮社区里
It's like living in a goddamn global hippie commune.
哦…那个…
Well...
罗纳德·里根说他要在88年竞选总统
Ronald Reagan says he's gonna be running for president in '88.
我们可以写一篇这个
We could run a piece on that.
西摩尔 我们不能用新闻来宣传荒谬的事
Seymour, we don't dignify absurdities with coverage.
这里还是美国 该死的
This is still America, damn it.
谁会想要一个牛仔入主白宫?
Who wants a cowboy in the White House?
好吧 呃…
Okay....
我可以去轶闻档案里找点东西
I could look for something in the crank file.
轶闻档案?
Crank file.
随便吧 自己主动一点
Whatever. Take some initiative.
想写什么就写什么 都交给你了
Run whatever you like. I leave it entirely in your hands.
罗夏日记 1985年10月12号
Rorschach's journal, October 12th, 1985.
今晚 笑匠死于纽约
Tonight, a comedian died in New York.